----- RussZ&S ---------
I was born 1911, Chickasaw County,Piedmont Plantation.
我生于1911年，Chickasaw县，Piedmont农场
And did you know,as a girl growing up,
那时你知道吗，在你还小的时候
that one day you'd be a maid?
有一天你将成为女仆
Yes, ma'am, I did.
是的，女士，我知道
And you knew that because...
你知道是因为...
My mama was a maid.My grandmama was a house slave.
我妈妈就是女仆. 而我奶奶是家奴。
House... slave.
家.....奴....
Do you ever dream of being something else?
你曾梦想过做点其他什么事吗？
What does it feel like to raise a white child
照顾一个白人小孩是什么滋味
when your own child's at home being looked after by somebody else?
当你自己的小孩在家被其他人照顾时？
It feel...
那感觉...
I done raised 17 kids in my life.
我一生照顾过17个孩子
Looking after white babies, that's what I do.
照顾白人小孩就是我的工作
Aibee, Aibee.
- Hi! - Aibee!
-嗨！ -Aibee!
I know how to get them babies to sleep, stop crying and go in the toilet bowl
我知道如何哄婴儿睡觉，停止哭泣，去厕所便便。
before their mamas even get out of bed in the morning
甚至在他们妈妈还赖在床上的时候
Babies like fat.
婴儿都喜欢胖的人
They like big fat legs, too. That I know.
他们也喜欢又粗又胖的腿。这些我都知道。
You is kind, you is smart...
你很善良，你很聪明...
...you is important.
...你很重要
- You is smart... - Smart...
-你很聪明... -聪明...
- ...you is kind... - ...you is kind...
-你很善良 -你很善良
- ...you is important. - ...you is important.
-你很重要 -你很重要
That's so good.
说得不错
很不错
I work for the Leefolts from eight to four; six days a week.
我为Leefolts工作，每天八点到四点，一周六天
I make 95 cent an hour. That comes to $182 every month.
我每小时挣95美分。这样每月就能挣182美元
I do all the cooking, cleaning, washing, ironing and grocery shopping.
烧饭，打扫，洗衣服，熨衣服，购买杂货 这些事我都做。
But mostly, I take care of Baby Girl.
但是最重要的，我照看小女孩
And, Lord, I worry she gonna be fat.
天啊，我真担心她会长成个肥妞
Mae Mobley.
Ain 't going to be no beauty queen either.
看来是不会成为选美冠军了
Aibileen, bridge club is in an hour. Did you finish the chicken salad?
Aibileen，桥牌俱乐部一小时后开始。鸡肉沙拉做好没？
- Yes. - Oh, and Hilly's deviled eggs.
-好了。 -哦，还有Hilly的芥末鸡蛋
- No paprika. - Mm-hm.
-不要加辣椒。 -嗯哼
Does this dress look homemade?
这件衣服看起来像家里做的吗？
I reckon when you finish it won't.
我想等你做好后就不像了
Well, thank you.
好，谢谢
Miss Leefolt still don't pick Baby Girl up but once a day.
Leefolt小姐一天只抱一次这小女孩
The birthing blues got hold of Miss Leefolt pretty hard.
产后忧郁症一直困扰着她
I done seen it happen plenty of times,
这样的事我见过很多次
once babies start having their own babies.
一旦小孩开始有了自己的小孩
And the young white ladies of Jackson...
而Jackson的年轻白人小姐...
...oh Lord, was they having babies.
天啊，他们也有小孩了吗
But not Miss Skeeter.
除了斯基特小姐
No man and no babies.
没有男人就没有小孩
- Morning. - Hi.
- 早 - 嗨
- My name is Eugenia Phelan, and... - Come on.
- 我叫Eugenia Phela... - 快点
Eugenia Phelan, Mr. Blackly.
Eugenia Phela，Blackly先生
Shut the damn door.
关上该死的门
I guarantee you, one day they're going to figure out cigarettes will kill you.
我向你保证，迟早有一天他们会发现香烟是致命的
OK, Miss Phelan, let's see what you got.
好，Phelan小姐，看看你怎么样吧
Murrah High: editor.
Murrah High：担任编辑
Ole Miss Rebel Rousert editor.
Ole Miss Rebel Rousert 任编辑
Double major.
双学位
Junior League: editor.
Junior League：任编辑
- Damn, girl, don't you have fun? - Is that important?
-唉，姑娘，你不会找点乐子吗？-那很重要吗？
- Do you have any references? - Yes.
- 你有推荐信吗？ - 是的
Right here.
这里
This...
这个...
This is a rejection letter.
这是一封拒绝信
Not exactly. See, Miss Stein thought...
并不算是。看，Stein小姐认为...
Stein?
Elaine Stein, from Harper and Row Publishing in New York.
纽约HARPER & ROW出版社的Elaine Stein
Oh, Lord.
哦，天
I'm gonna be a serious writer, Mr. Blackly
我会是一个严肃的作者，布莱克利先生
I applied for a job, but Mrs. Stein thought...
我应聘过一份工作，但Stein小姐认为
She said no.
她说不行
Well, until I gain some experience.
是的，直到我有工作经验
See? Says right there.
看？那里写着
"Great potential. Gain some experience and please apply again."
潜力巨大，获得工作经验后请再次应聘工作
Oh, Christ. I guess you'll do. Do you clean?
哦，天啊。我想你能行。你会清洁吗？
- I'm sorry. Clean? - Clean.
- 抱歉，清洁？ - 清洁
Grab that basket.
拿上那个筐子
Miss Myrna has gone shit-house crazy on us.
Myrna小姐死后留给我们一个烂摊子
She drunk hairspray or something.
她喝了洗发定型剂或者其它什么
I want you to read her past columns.
我想你先读读她以前的专栏
Then read these letters and you answer them just like she would.
看看这些信，然后像她那样回复它
Nobody is gonna know the damn difference.
没人会发现有什么不同
You know who Miss Myrna is?
你知道Myrna小姐吗
I read her articles all the time.
我一直都有读她的文章
Articles? Miss Phelan, it's a cleaning advice column.
文章？Phelan小姐，这是一个家政清洁建议的专栏
Eight bucks a week. Copy is due on Thursday.
周薪八美元。每周四交稿
- Hello?
- 你好？
Lou Ann, honey, I can't talk right now. I'm at work.
Lou Ann，亲爱的，我现在不方便说话，我在工作
What? Shut that goddamn door.
什么？关上该死的门
Mama, we're late for bridge!
妈妈，打桥牌我们要迟了！
Miss Hilly was the first of the babies to have a baby.
Hilly小姐是第一个有了孩子的小孩
...three...
...三...
And it must have come out of her like the 11th Commandment,
而事情由她就此开始，就像11戒律一样
'cause once Miss Hilly had a baby,
一旦Hilly小姐有了孩子
every girl at the bridge table had to have one, too.
一起打桥牌的每个女孩不得不也生一个
Minny, go get Mama!
Minny，快去叫妈妈
Missus Walters, you need help coming down?
Walters太太，下楼你需要帮助吗？
- I'm down. - Ooh.
-我在下面了 -哦
- I been down. - Give me a heart attack.
-我一直在下面 -让我心脏病犯
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Missus Walters. Here, let me help you.
Walters太太，这里，让我帮你。
Take that off. It's 98 degrees out there.
脱掉那件，外面37摄氏度
- ls it? - Yes, ma'am.
-是吗？ -是的，夫人。
Well, let's put my coat on then.
好，那我还是穿上外套吧
- Come on, Minny. - All right.
- 快点，Minny - 好的
- Here's your pocketbook. - Thank you.
-给，你的皮夹  -谢谢
OK, let me get the pie.
好，我去把馅饼拿上
Hold on, Missus Walters. Hold on.
等等，Walters太太。等等
Once Missus Walters' arteries went hard, Miss Hilly moved her into her house
Walters太太得了动脉硬化后，Hilly小姐就让她搬进她家
and fired the maid she had to make room for Minny too.
之前的女仆被开除了以给Minny腾出点空间
See, Minny about the best cook in Mississippi,
看，Minny，密西西比最好的厨子
and Miss Hilly wanted her.
Hilly小姐想得到她
I lost my own boy, Treelore, four years ago.
四年前，我失去了自己的小孩，Treelore
After that, I just didn't want to live no more.
那之后，我也不想活了
It took God and Minny to get me through it.
是上帝和Minny帮我渡过难关
Minny my best friend. Old lady like me lucky to have her.
Minny我的好朋友，像我这样的老妇能有她作伴真是幸运
After my boy died, a bitter seed was planted inside of me.
我的孩子死后，苦味的种子开始在我心里生根发芽
And I just didn't feel so accepting anymore.
我也不再感觉得到认同
No.
不
You drunk up two glasses of grape juice. I know you got to tee-tee.
你刚喝下两杯葡萄汁。我知道你要尿尿
No.
不
I'll give you two cookies if you go.
如果你尿我就给你两块曲奇
Mae Mobley, you're going!
Mae Mobley，你做到了！
Aibileen, the girls are pulling up, and the table isn't set.
Aibileen，她们在停车了，桌子还没摆好
Mae Mobley go, Mama.
Mae Mobley 走开，妈妈
Get in your room right now.
马上回你的房间去
Set out the dessert forks. Please.
摆上甜点用的叉子
Put Mama in a chair before she breaks a hip.
把妈妈扶进椅子，在她摔了屁股前
I'm not deaf yet, Hilly.
我不是聋子，Hilly
- Hey, girls.
-嗨，女士们
Oh. Minny. Will you see if Aibileen has some of that ambrosia?
哦，Minny. 你去看看Aibileen那还有好吃的吗
Hold on. Those are Miss Hilly's.
等等，这是Hilly小姐的
She looks like the winning horse at the Kentucky Derby.
她就像在肯塔基赢了赛马一样
- All flowers and bows.
春风得意
Got to have paprika on them.
撒上辣椒粉
Ooh.
哦
Forgive me, Lord, but I'm gonna have to kill that woman, Aibileen.
原谅我，主，我非得杀了那女人，Aibileen
Now she gone to putting pencil marks on my toilet paper.
她开始在我的厕纸上乱画了
- Did she? - Mm-hm.
- 她真这样？ -嗯哼
But I carry paper in from my own damn house. That fool don't know.
我有从自己家带纸过去，那笨蛋不知道
Miss Leefolt got so much hairspray on her head
Leefolt小姐在她头上弄了那么多定型剂
she gonna blow us all up if she light a cigarette.
她会把我们都炸飞的 如果她点上一支烟
And you know she will!
你知道她一定会的
- You got some ambrosia? - You know I do.
-美食都准备好了？ -你知道我会的
All right, I'll be back.
好的，我马上回来
Minny, cord, girl.
Minny，绳子
Shut up.
闭嘴
Hi, Missus Walters.
嗨，Walters太太
I'm watching my story.
我正看电视呢
OK.
好
Isn't it gorgeous?
很漂亮吧？
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉我迟了
You're home!
你回家了！
I missed you all, too.
我想死大家了
Well, if it isn't "Long Haul" Skeeter.
真是好久不见 Skeeter
We didn't ever think you'd leave Ole Miss.
我们从没想到你还会离开Ole Miss（密西西比大学的简称）
Well, it does take four years, Jolene.
四年时间不短啊，Jolene
I've got a great summer planned for you.
我为你准备了一个精彩的夏天节目
Great.
棒极了
I went ahead and I picked up my black dress from the cleaners this morning.
今早我去干洗店取了我的黑色礼服
What?
什么？
- About supper club tonight. - What?
-关于今晚的晚餐聚会 -什么？
Honey, Stuart had to cancel.
亲爱的，Stuart取消了
- Again?
- 又一次？
He got held up on the oil rig, Skeeter.
他因为石油钻井耽搁了，Skeeter
It's... It's offshore.
那是..那是在海上
I'm starting to think this Stuart is a figment of your imagination,
我开始认为这个Stuart是你想象虚构出来的了
so just forget it.
那就忘掉吧
I'm just gonna go get a plate.
我去拿个盘子
- Shh! - Sorry!
- 嘘！ - 抱歉
I got a job today.
我今天找到一份工作
At The Jackson Journal.
在Jackson日报
They'd be a fool not to hire you.
他们要不雇你的话就是傻子
- To Skeeter and her job.
敬Skeeter和她的工作
Last stop till marriage.
婚前的最后一站
Oh!
哦
- it's for the Miss Myrna column. - Hmm.
-Myrna小姐的专栏 -嗯
Elizabeth, can I talk to Aibileen?
Elizabeth，我能和Aibileen谈谈吗？
Just to help me with some of the letters till I get a knack for it.
帮我回复下这些信直到我能熟练应对
My Aibileen?
我的Aibileen？
Why can't you just get Constantine to help?
为什么不去找Constantine帮你？
- Constantine quit us. - [all gasping]
-Constantine离开了我们
Oh, my gosh. Skeeter, I'm so sorry.
哦，我的天. Skeeter，抱歉
Anyway, I just, um... I don't really know how to answer these letters.
总之，我...我真不知道如何回复这些信
Well, I mean, as long as it doesn't interfere with her work.
好的，只要别打扰到她工作
I don't see why not.
我不明白为什么不行
Leefolt residence.
Leefolt家
Hello. Is Elizabeth in?
你好，Elizabeth在吗
She having bridge club right now. May I take a message?
她正在打桥牌，可以帮你留个言吗？
Yes, please tell her Celia Foote called again.
好，请告诉她Celia Foote又打了一次电话
I'll call back tomorrow.
我明天还会打来
- Yes, ma'am. - Uh...
-是的，夫人 - 哦
Miss?
小姐？
I'm looking for some help at my house. Do you know any maids looking?
我家里需要点帮助，你知道上哪找女仆吗？
No, ma'am.
不，夫人
OK. It's Celia Foote.
好的，是Celia Foote
Emerson-684. Bye now.
地址Emerson-684 再见
You scared the daylights out of me!
吓死我了！
It is lunchtime, and I am suddenly hungry.
午饭时间到，我饿了
Honestly!
真坏！
Oh.
哦
I'm still working on it, Aibileen.
我还在吃呢，Aibileen
Who was that on the phone?
刚才谁打电话来？
Miss Celia Foote called again.
Celia Foote小姐又打来一次
I've never called her back, Hilly.
我从没回过她电话，Hilly
She can't take a hint, can she?
她难道就真不明白其中的暗示？
Who's Celia Foote?
谁是Celia Foote
That tacky girl Johnny married.
Johnny娶的那个俗气女孩
From Sugar Ditch.
来自Sugar Ditch
It could have been you, Hilly.
新娘本该是你的，Hilly
And live 30 minutes outside of town? No, thank you.
离市区30分钟路程？才不要，谢谢
Anyway, I ran into her at the beauty parlor, and she had the nerve to ask
总之，我在美容店遇到她，她居然敢问我
if she could help with the Children's Benefit Ball.
她能否参与孩子的义卖舞会
Aren't we taking non-members? The benefit has gotten so big.
我们不是在招收新会员吗？义卖现在这么火？
Yes, but we're not telling her.
是，但我们不会告诉她
Thank you, Aibileen.
谢谢你，Aibileen
Hilly, I wish you'd just go use the bathroom.
Hilly，你去用一下卫生间吧
I'm fine.
我很好
Oh, she's just upset
哦，她只是有点烦
because the nigra uses the guest bath and so do we.
因为黑人用宾客卫生间，而我们也是
Aibileen, go check on Mae Mobley.
Aibileen，去看看Mae Mobley
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
Just go use mine and Raleigh's.
用我和Raleigh的好了
If Aibileen uses the guest bath, I'm sure she uses yours, too.
如果Aibileen用了宾客卫生间，我敢保证她也用过你的
She does not.
她不会
Wouldn't you rather them take their business outside?
你不会让她们在外面解决掉这些事吗？
Have you all seen the cover of Life this week?
你们看过这周Life的封面了吗？
Jackie's never looked more regal.
Jackie看起来真豪华
Tell Raleigh every penny he spends on a colored's bathroom
告诉Raleigh每一分他都花在了有色人种的厕所上
he'll get back in spades when y'all sell.
这点小钱他马上就能赚回来
it's just plain dangerous. They carry different diseases than we do.
太危险了，黑人携带着各种疾病
Pass.
过
That's why I've drafted the Home Health Sanitation Initiative.
所以我才起草了家庭健康与环境卫生的倡议
The what?
什么？
A disease-preventative bill
一个预防疾病的法案
that requires every white home to have a separate bathroom for the colored help.
要求每个白人家庭提供一个单独供有色人种使用的卫生间
It's been endorsed by the White Citizens' Council.
这法案受到了白人市民议会的支持
Maybe we should just build you a bathroom outside, Hilly.
也许我们该为你在外面建个厕所，Hilly
You ought not to joke about the colored situation.
你不该拿有色人种的问题来开玩笑
I'll do whatever it takes to protect our children.
我会采取一切措施来保护我们的孩子
Your lead, Elizabeth.
该你了，Elizabeth
- Aibileen? - Yes, ma'am.
-Aibileen？ -是的，夫人
Do you think you'd be willing to help me with those Miss Myrna letters?
你愿意帮我回复下Myrna小姐的那些信吗？
Miss Myrna get it wrong a lot of times. Be good to get it right.
Myrna小姐经常犯错，能纠正一下很不错
Thank you, Aibileen.
谢谢，Aibileen
All that talk in there today...
今天他们说的那番话...
Hilly'S talk?
Hilly说的那些？
I'm sorry you had to hear that.
很抱歉让你听到那些
Is that Preacher Green's sermon?
那是Green牧师的布道吗？
Yes, ma'am, it is.
是的，夫人
That reminds me so much of my maid, Constantine.
那让我想起了我家里的女仆Constantine
I know Constantine. We're in church circle together.
我认识Constantine，我们去同一个教堂
Have you seen her lately?
最近你有见过她吗？
No, ma'am.
没有，夫人
Did you know that she had quit us?
你知道她离开我们了吗？
Quit?
离开？
I got home from school a week ago, and my mama told me she had quit.
一周前我从学校回到家，老妈告诉我她离开了
Back in March, she went to live with her daughter, Rachel. In Chicago.
说她三月时回芝加哥和她女儿Rachel一起生活去了
Did you hear that? Do you have her phone number?
这事你知道吗？你知道她电话号码吗？
There you are, Skeeter.
你在这呢，Skeeter
Hilly wants you to put her initiative in the League newsletter.
Hilly要你把她的倡议放到俱乐部的时事通讯上
OK.
好的
I'll be back tomorrow, Aibileen,
我明天还会再来，Aibileen
to get started on those Miss Myrna letters.
开始搞那些Myrna小姐的信件
Y'all make it quick.
你们动作都快点
Tomorrow is silver-polishing day. OK?
明天是“银装日”。好吗？
Hi, Jameso.
嗨，Jameso.
How you, Miss Eugenia?
你好，Eugenia小姐
Mama?
妈妈？
Mama.
妈妈
Yoo-hoo.
Mama?
妈妈？
Back here, honey!
在这里，亲爱的！
Is this a little too young?
是不是太年轻了点？
That's a little too everything.
这打扮有点太过头了
Oh, hell. You're right.
哦，该死，你说得对
OK.
好的
Much better.
好多了
Your daddy bought me this dress in '58.
你爸爸在58年给我买的这件衣服
Mama, I want to ask you about Constantine.
妈妈，我想问你些事 关于Constantine
Right after Ole Miss won the Sugar Bowl. Come on. You try it on.
那是在Ole Miss（大学）赢了Sugar Bowl(美国一项橄榄球赛事)之后，快，你来试下衣服
What really happened?
到底发生了什么？
Skeeter, your mother is sick. She wants to see you in this dress.
Skeeter，你妈妈生病了，她想看你穿这身衣服
Unzip me.
拉开拉链
Come on.
快点
Did I tell you Fanny Peatrow got engaged?
我有告诉过你Peatrow订婚了吗？
After she got that teller job,
就在她成为出纳员之后
her mother said she was swimming in proposals.
她妈妈说她被各种求婚包围
Good for fair Fanny Peatrow.
对Peatrow来说真好
Eugenia, your eggs are dying. Would it kill you to go on a date?
Eugenia，你的卵子真在死亡，你出去约个会又不会死？
Just show a little gumption. Careful now, careful.
表现出点魄力。小心点，小心
Oh, now look at this.
哦，快瞧瞧
This dress is just precious on you.
这衣服你穿上真漂亮
Just take it in a little here. Little there.
就是这里要改小些，还有那里
- Get your hair fixed. - I got a job today.
-再给你做个头发 -我今天找到份工作
Where?
哪里？
Writing for The Jackson Journal.
Jackson日报
- Great.
-棒极了
You can write my obituary!
以后我的讣告交给你了！
"Charlotte Phelan, dead! Her daughter, still single."
“Charlotte Phelan去世！她的女儿仍然单身！”
Mother, would it really be so bad if I never met a husband?
我没遇上一个老公就真这么糟吗，妈妈
Skeeter! Skeeter!
Skeeter!
I need to ask you something.
我想问你些事情
I read the other day about how some girls get unbalanced.
我读到过一篇文章，关于女孩们如何迷失自我
They start thinking these...
他们会开始产生...
...unnatural thoughts.
...一些不正常的想法
Are you...
你还...
Do you, uh... find men attractive?
你还...觉得男人有吸引力吗？
Are you having unnatural thoughts about girls or women?
还是你对女孩或妇女更有兴趣？
Oh, my God.
哦，我的天
Because this article says there's a cure. A special root tea!
因为这篇文章说这有得治，有一个特制的茶饮
Mother, I want to be with girls as much as you want to be with Jameso.
妈妈，我想和女孩们在一起就像你想和Jameso在一起一样
- Eugenia! - Unless, of course, you do!
-Eugenia！-除非，你是真想！
Oh!
哦
Carlton's bringing Rebecca to dinner. Try to look presentable!
Carlton会带Rebecca来吃饭。打扮下自己！
What the hell you know about cleaning a house, Skeeter?
关于打扫房屋你能知道什么，Skeeter?
It's a start, Carlton.
这只是开始，Carlton.
If you say so. I thought you wanted to write books.
既然你这样说，我以为你想自己写书
Now, y'all leave Sister alone.
快，你们都别烦你姐姐了
- I'm proud of you, sweetheart. - The irony of it all.
-我为你自豪，甜心  -真是讽刺啊
Giving advice on how to keep up a home when she doesn't even...
为打扫房屋提出建议而她自己甚至都不...
Oh, no, Pascagoula. You couldn't have known this, but I'm allergic to almonds.
哦，不，Pascagoula。你不知道吧，我对杏仁过敏
Sorry, Miss Eugenia, I'll get you another one.
抱歉，Eugenia小姐，我重新给你拿一个
You know, last time I had an almond, I stopped liking men.
上次我吃了个杏仁，从此我对男人不再感兴趣了
Oh, my Lord.
哦，我的天
Oh, no, Rebecca, it's fine. There's a special root tea for that now.
不，Rebecca，没关系，现在有一个特制茶饮专治这个。
You have pushed it, young lady.
你别逼我，小姐
Daddy. What happened to Constantine?
爸爸，Constantine到底怎么了？
Uh, well...
嗯，这个...
Constantine went to live in Chicago with her family.
Constantine回芝加哥和她的家庭一起生活
People move on, Skeeter.
人是向前看的，Skeeter
But I do wish that she'd stayed down here with us.
我真心希望她能留下来和我们在一起
I don't believe you.
我不相信你
She would've written and told me.
她该会写信告诉我的
Did you fire her?
你把她开除了吧？
We were just a job to her, honey. With them, it's all about money.
宝贝，对于她来说我们只是差事。她们要的只是钱。
You'll understand that once you've hired help of your own.
等你自己雇佣帮手的时候你会明白的
- She raised me. - She did not!
-是她把我带大的 -她没有
She worked here for 29 years!
她在这工作了29年！
It was a colored thing and I put it behind me!
有色人种的事而已，我都不再想了！
Excuse me a moment, Rebecca. My daughter has upset my cancerous ulcers.
不好意思，Rebecca。我的女儿让我癌症犯病了
What you doing hiding out here, girl?
你一个人躲这干嘛呢，女孩？
I couldn't tell Mama I didn't get asked to the dance.
我不敢告诉妈妈我没收到去舞会的邀请
It's all right.
没关系
Some things we just got to keep to ourselves, right?
一些事本该只有我们自己才知道，对吧？
All the boys say I'm ugly.
那些小子都说我丑
Mama was third runner-up in the Miss South Carolina pageant.
妈妈可是南卡罗莱纳州小姐的第三个亚军
I wish you'd quit feeling sorry for yourself.
我希望你不再为自己感到歉意
Now, that's ugly.
那样的你才丑
Ugly is something that goes up inside you.
丑是在你心里生长出来的
It's mean and hurtful, like them boys.
它刻薄又伤人，就像那些小子
Now you're not one of them, is you?
你不是那些人，对吧？
I didn't think so, honey.
我想你不是，亲爱的
Every day...
每一天...
Every day you're not dead in the ground,
你还没入土的每一天
when you wake up in the morning, you're gonna have to make some decisions.
当你早晨醒过来时，你得做出决定
Got to ask yourself this question:
这样问你自己：
"Am I gonna believe
“我要不要相信
all them bad things them fools say about me today?"
那些傻瓜说的关于我的坏话？”
You hear me?
听到了吗？
"Am I gonna believe all them bad things
“我要不要相信那些
them fools say about me today'?"
傻瓜说的关于我的坏话？
Au right?
好吗？
As for your mama, she didn't pick her life.
至于你妈妈，她没有选择她的生活
It picked her.
生活选择了她
But you...
但你...
...you're gonna do something big with yours.
...你将会用你的生活干出点大事
You wait and see.
等着瞧吧
Come on, go home with me till the dance over. Come on.
快，等舞会结束和我回家
Miss Stein, you said in your letter to write about what disturbs me,
Stein小姐，你在信里说要写下困扰自己的事
particularly if it bothers no one else.
特别是只困扰自己的事
Come on.
快
And I understand that now.
我现在有点明白了
Continue.
继续
I'd like to write something from the point of view of the help.
我想写点东西，从女佣的角度
These colored women raise white children,
这些照料白人小孩的有色人种
and in 20 years, those children become the boss.
二十年后，这些小孩成为老板
We love them and they love us,
我们爱她们，她们也爱我们
but they can't even use the toilets in our houses.
但是她们甚至不能使用我们房里的厕所
Don't you find that ironic, Miss Stein?
你不觉得这个很讽刺吗，Stein小姐？
I'm listening.
我在听
Margaret Mitchell glorified the mammy figure,
Margaret Mitchell （《乱世佳人》作者）美化了黑人保姆的形象
- who dedicates her whole life
一个将她一声奉献给
to a white family.
白人家庭的黑人
But nobody ever asked Mammy how she felt about it.
但从没有人问过黑人保姆她自己感觉怎样
So, a side to this never before heard?
所以这方面从没被人提过？
Yes.
是的
'Cause nobody ever really talks about it down here.
因为这边没人关心这个
Skeeter, who are you talking to in there?
Skeeter，你在和谁说话呢？
Go away!
走开！
- Who was that? - My mother.
-那是谁？ -我妈妈
Look.
看
No maid in her right mind is ever gonna tell you the truth.
脑子正常的女仆是不会跟你谈论这个的
That's a hell of a risk to take in a place like Jackson, Mississippi.
在密西西比Jackson这地方，谈论这个风险很大
I already have a maid.
我已经找到一个女仆
Really? A Negro maid has already agreed to speak with you?
真的？一个黑人女仆已经同意和你谈论这个？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，女士
Well... I guess I can read what you come up with.
那好...等你写好后我会看看的
The book biz could use a little rattling.
出版界需要点不同的声音
Thank you, Miss Stein.
谢谢你，Stein小姐
Hey, hey, hey, all I'm saying
嘿，嘿，嘿，我的意思是
is that I'll let you know if it's even worth pursuing.
我只会告诉你这故事是否值得深入挖掘
And for God's sake, you're a 23-year-old educated woman.
上帝啊，你是一个23岁受过教育的妇女了
Go get yourself an apartment.
给你自己找间公寓吧
"Dear Miss Myrna:
“亲爱的Myrna小姐：
When I'm chopping onions, how do I keep tears out of my eyes?"
当我在切洋葱的时候怎么才能不流泪？
Shoot, that's easy. You tell her hold a matchstick between her teeth.
这好办.你告诉她用火柴棒撑开她的嘴巴就行
Is it lit?
火柴要点燃嘛？
No, ma'am.
不，女士
Miss Leefolt said you could start right away.
Leefolt小姐说你可以马上开始动工
Build it just like the bathroom at my house. Let's see.
建一个就像我房里那样的卫生间. 让我看看
- Right there. That will be nice. - Yes, ma'am.
-就在那里. 建那不错. -是的，夫人
My goodness, we got to run back to the car. Come on.
我的天，我们得快回车里去. 快
Bye, Skeeter!
再见，Skeeter!
Aibileen.
There's something else I want to write about. I would need your help.
有些其它的事我想写，我需要你的帮助
I want to interview you about what it's like to work as a maid.
我想采访下你，谈谈作为一个女仆的感受
I'd like to do a book of interviews about working for white families.
我想写本书关于为白人家庭工作
And we could show what it's like to work for, say, Elizabeth?
我们谈谈为这些人工作是什么滋味，例如，为Elizabeth？
You know what Miss Leefolt do to me if she knew I was telling stories on her?
你明白Leefolt小姐知道我背地里谈论她后会怎么对我吗？
I was thinking that we wouldn't have to tell her.
我在想我们不必一定得告诉她
The other maids would have to keep it a secret, too.
其她女仆也会把这事当做秘密守护好的
Other maids?
其她女仆？
I was hoping to get four or five.
我希望能找四到五个
To show what it's really like in Jackson.
来展示Jackson这地方到底是个啥样
Show what y'all get paid, and the babies and the bathrooms.
展示下你们所得到的，婴儿和卫生间这些事
The good and the bad.
好的坏的方面都写
I bought you this damn house. I put up with your new clothes
为你我买下这间该死的房子. 忍受你的那些新衣服
and trips to New Orleans, but this takes the goddamn cake.
还有去新奥尔良旅行，但这太过火了
Hilly spoke to the surgeon general,
Hilly和卫生局局长谈过
and she also said it'll add value to our home.
她还说这会增加我们房屋的价值
I guess Mae Mobley can go to college in that damn bathroom!
难道Mae Mobley靠那破卫生间就能去上大学
Hilly's covering the cost and said
这些费用Hilly全包了，她还说
you could just do William's taxes to pay her back.
你帮William缴税就算还她钱了
We don't take orders from the Holbrooks.
我们不接受Holbrooks的指挥
Skeeter, how you doing?
Skeeter，你好吗？
Fine.
不错
Fix me a sandwich, Aibileen.
给我做个三明治，Aibileen
Aibileen, Mae Mobley's crying her eyes out.
Aibileen，Mae Mobley哭的好厉害
Skeeter.
I'm sorry, but I think it's best if you leave now.
抱歉，我想你现在最好先离开
Oh, sure, sure.
哦，当然
And this Miss Myrna thing isn't going to work out with Aibileen.
Myrna小姐这件事Aibileen帮不上你
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You're making it hotter, flapping your arms like that, Minny.
你搞得我更热了，像那样扇，Minny
Look how big the waves are, Minny.
看这波浪好大啊，Minny
Let's go to the beach. Run, get Mr. Walters!
我们去海滩吧.快，叫上Walters先生！
He loves riding these waves!
他最爱乘波踏浪了！
You know we went to Biloxi on our honeymoon?
你知道 我们蜜月去的Biloxi
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
Are we in Biloxi, Minny?
我们这是在Biloxi吗，Minny?
No, ma'am. We ain't.
不，夫人. 我们不在
Why don't you sit down here for a spell.
你干嘛不坐一会儿呢
And then me and you will go on down to the beach in a little while.
然后过会儿我们一起去海滩
How about that?
怎么样？
Uh...
嗯...
Miss Hilly?
Hilly小姐？
Mm-hm?
嗯哼？
Never mind.
没事
You go on ahead and use the inside bath, Minny, it's all right.
去吧，用屋里的厕所，Minny，没关系
Oh, for crying out loud, it's just a little rain.
哦，不至于吧，就这点毛毛雨
She can go on up and get an umbrella from William's study.
她去William的书房拿把雨伞就好
I believe she was working for me before you dragged us both here.
她是为我工作的 在你把我们带到这里之前
Daddy ruined you.
你被你爸教废了
I'm just gonna get your tea.
我去帮你拿些茶
Minny?
Minny, are you in there?
Minny，你在里面吗？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
And just what are you doing?
你在里面干什么呢？
Get off my toilet!
滚出我的厕所！
You are fired, Minny Jackson!
你被解雇了，Minny Jackson!
Go on!
继续吧！
Eighteen people died in Jackson that day.
那天Jackson 18人丧生
Ten white and eight black.
10个白人 8个黑人
God don't pay no mind to color once He decide to set a tornado loose.
龙卷风下上帝不分肤色 人人平等
Aibee's here, honey.
Aibee在这，宝贝
Aibee's here.
Aibee在这
Hurry, Aibileenl Mae Mobley is up, and I'm off to the doctor!
快，Aibileen！Mae Mobley醒来了，我要去医生那！
That's Aibee's bathroom, Mama. Hey, Aibee!
那是Aibee的厕所，妈妈. 嗨，Aibee！
No, no, no, honey. Promise me you won't go in there, OK?
不行，宝贝. 答应我绝不去那里面，好吗？
- Yes, ma'am.
-是的，夫人
I'm right here, Baby Girl.
我就在这里，宝贝！
Isn't it so nice to have your own, Aibileen?
有自己的卫生间很不错吧，Aibileen?
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
You're my real mama, Aibee.
你才是我的妈妈，Aibee.
- Is that Minny? - Minny.
-是Minny吗？ -Minny
Hey, Aibileen!
嗨,Aibileen!
Hey, Minny!
嗨，Minny!
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼
Where you headed?
你去哪？
I got some business to tend to, so y'all just mind your own.
我要去处理些私事，你们管好自己吧
All right, then. Well, bye!
那好. 再见！
Bye!
再见！
Now is she mad at me 'cause I got that job at Miss Hilly's?
她因为我得到Hilly小姐那的工作而恼火吗？
Don't worry about her. She always mad about something.
别担心她，总有事会让她恼火
Aibileen.
Yes, ma'am. Everything OK?
是的，女士. 一切都好？
Yeah, I just wanted to talk to you.
是的，我只想和你谈谈
You got some more Miss Myrna questions for me?
你还要问我那些Myrna小姐的问题?
Oh, no, I just wanted to talk about...
不，我想谈...
We never finished our conversation at Elizabeth's.
在Elizabeth家的那些谈话我们还没谈完
About that book I want to write?
关于那本我想写的书？
I'd really like to interview you, Aibileen.
我真想采访你，Aibileen.
I know it's scary.
我知道这有点吓人
They set my cousin Shinelle's car on fire,
他们把我堂妹Shinelle的车给烧了
just 'cause she went down to the voting station.
就因为她去选举站投票
A book like this has never been written before.
这方面的书之前从没有人写过
'Cause there's a reason.
这是有原因的
I do this with you, I might as well burn my own house down.
我和你这样做，我的房子也会被烧掉
I promise we'll be careful.
我保证我们会很小心
This already ain't careful, Miss Skeeter!
我们这样说话就很不小心，Skeeter小姐！
You not knowing that is what's scaring me the most.
你不知道到底是什么在吓我.
Scare me more than Jim Crow.
种族隔离法都没能这样吓到我
An right.
好吧
Here's my phone number.
这是我的电话号码
- My car's here. I could take you home. - No, ma'am.
-我的车在这，我可以送你回家 -不用，女士
"No person shall require any white female
“任何人不得要求白人女性
to nurse in wards or rooms in which Negro men are placed.
在有黑人的病房或房间哺乳
Books shall not be interchangeable between the white and colored schools,
白人和有色人种学校间的书籍不可互换
but shall continue to be used by the race Hrst using them.
只得由第一个使用它们的人种继续使用
No colored barber shall serve as a barber to white women or girls.
有色人种的理发师不得给白人女性理发
- Any person printing, publishing
任何人擅自印刷，出版或传播
or circulating written matter
要求社会或公众
urging for public acceptance or social equality between whites and Negroes
平等对待白人与黑人的刊物
is subject to imprisonment. "
都将被监禁”
Hello?
你好？
Aibileen, I done went and did it now.
Aibileen, 现在我做到了
I went to Miss Hilly's house this afternoon.
下午我去Hilly小姐家
Why Minny?
为什么 Minny?
She done told every white woman in town I'm a thief
她告诉镇里的每个白人妇女 说我是贼
Said I stole a candelabra.
说我偷了个烛台
But I got her back.
但我现在还给她了
What you did?
你做了什么？
I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你
I ain 't telling nobody.
我不会告诉任何人
I done something terrible awful to that woman,
我对那女人干了很糟的事
and now she know what I done.
现在她知道我的能耐了
Sorry.
抱歉
Minny.
She got what she deserved, Aibileen.
她罪有应得，Aibileen.
But now I ain't gonna never get no job again.
但我将再也找不到工作
Oh, Lord, Leroy gonna kill me.
哦，上帝，Leroy会杀了我的
Leroy?
What you done did now, Minny?
你都干了些什么，Minny?
- Get off that phone, woman! - Leroy, please!
-放下电话，女人！ -Leroy，拜托！
Minny? Minny!
Please! Please!
拜托！
Come here!
过来！
Please open your Bibles to Exodus.
请将圣经翻到旧约第二卷
Chapter four, verse ten.
第四章，第十节
God, having asked Moses to free the Israelites...
上帝，要求摩西释放以色列人
...Moses answered:
...摩西回应：
"Oh, my Lord. I am not eloquent.
“哦，主，我不胜雄辩
I am slow of speech and slow of tongue."
我语拙口笨.”
See, courage isn't just about being brave.
看，勇气不只是勇敢
Amen!
阿门！
Courage is daring to do what is right
勇气是敢于去做对的事
in spite of the weakness of our flesh.
不惜我们凡夫肉身
And God tells us,
上帝告诉我们
commands us, compels us,
指挥我们，驱使我们
-to love. Amen? - Amen.
-去爱. 阿门 -阿门
See, love,
看，爱
as exemplified by our Lord Jesus Christ,
以我主耶稣基督为例
is to be prepared to put yourself in harm's way
他时刻准备着涉身险地
-for your fellow man.
为了你的子民
And by your fellow man, I mean your brother,
而借由你的子民，你的兄弟
your sister, your neighbor, your friend and your enemy.
你的姐妹，邻居，朋友和敌人
If you can love your enemy, you already have the victory.
如果你能爱你的敌人，那你已经胜利
Let's stand. All right.
请起立. 好的
Quick. Come quick.
快. 快点
I parked way up on State Street and caught a cab here, like you asked.
我把车停在街那头，然后打车到这，照你吩咐那样
Got dropped two streets over?
两个街区外下的车？
Mm-hm.
嗯
I know now that it's against the law, what we're doing.
我明白现在我们所作所为是违法的
I've never seen you out of uniform before.
我从没见过你不穿制服
You look really nice.
你看起来真漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢
I ain't never had no white person in my house before.
我从没让白人进过家里
Miss Skeeter...
Skeeter小姐...
...what if you don't like what I got to say... about white people?
如果你不喜欢我将要说的话...关于白人的？
This isn't about me.
这不关乎我
It doesn't matter how I feel.
我的感受不重要
You gonna have to change my name. Mine, Miss Leefolt's. Everybody.
你必须更改我的名字. 我的，Leefolt小姐的，所有人的
Do you have other maids that are interested?
你还认识其她感兴趣的女仆吗？
That gonna be hard.
不大可能
What about Minny?
那Minny呢？
Minny got her some stories, sure enough,
当然,Minny有她自己的故事
but she ain't real keen on talking to white peoples right now.
但她现在对和白人讲话不感兴趣
What does it feel like to raise a white child
照顾一个白人小孩是什么感觉
when your own child's at home being looked after by somebody else?
当你自己的小孩在家被别人照顾时？
It feel...
那感觉...
Is that your son?
这是你儿子吗？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，女士
Can we move on to the next question?
跳到下一个问题吧?
You don't have to call me ma'am.
你不必叫我女士
Not here.
在这里不必
Uh...
嗯...
Do you want to talk about the bathroom?
你想谈谈关于卫生间的事吗？
Or anything about Miss Leefolt?
或者关于Leefolt小姐的？
How she pays you, or has she ever yelled at you in front of Mae Mobley?
她是怎么支付你的，或者她有没有当着Mae Mobley面吼过你？
I thought I might write my stories down and read them to you.
我想我该把自己的故事写下来读给你听
Ain't no different than writing down my prayers.
就和我写祷文一样
OK.
好
Sure.
当然
I don't say my prayers out loud.
我不会把我的祷文大声念出来
I can get my point across a lot better writing them down.
写下这些话更能表达出我的观点
I write an hour, sometimes two, every night.
每晚我会花一小时，有时两小时来写
And after my prayers last night, I got some stories down, too.
昨晚就在我写完祷文后，我也写了点故事
Go ahead.
继续
"My first white baby to ever look after
“我照顾的第一个白人小孩
was named Alton Carrington Speers.
名叫Alton Carrington Speers
It was 1925, and I had just turned 14.
那是在1925年，我刚满14岁
I dropped out of school to help Mama with the bills.
我辍学来帮妈妈维持生计
Alton's mama died of lung disease."
Alton的妈妈死于肺病.”
I loved that baby. And he loved me.
我爱死那小孩了.他也爱我
That's when I learned I could make children feel proud of theyself
就在那时我发现我可以教会孩子为自己感到自豪
Alton used to always be asking me how come I was black.
Alton过去经常问我 我怎么是黑人
Just ate him up.
这问题折磨死他了
And one time, I told him it was because I drank too much coffee.
一次我告诉他我是黑人因为我喝太多咖啡
You should have seen his face.
你真该看看他的表情
This was just so great.
这真是太好了
I can't tell you how much I appreciate your doing this with me.
你能这样做我真是感激不尽
What changed your mind?
是什么改变了你的主意？
God.
上帝
And Miss Hilly Holbrook.
还有Hilly Holbrook小姐
Miss Hilly, I would like to ask you and Mr. William something.
Hilly小姐，我想问你和William先生一些事
My twin boys graduated from high school, both on the honor roll.
我的双胞胎刚高中毕业，都是优等生
Me and my husband, we been saving for years to send them to Tougaloo.
我和丈夫存钱很多年以便送他们去Tougaloo
We're short about $75 on one of the tuitions.
他们中的一个学费还差75美元
Whoo! I am late. I gotta get going.
哇！我迟了.我得走了
See you tonight, honey.
晚上见，宝贝
OK.
好
Go on.
继续
Well, now we're...
现在我们...
...faced with having to choose
...面临抉择
which son can go if we don't come up with the money.
到底送哪个孩子去上学 如果钱不够的话
Would you consider giving us a Ioan?
你能借我们一些钱吗？
I'd work every day for free till it was paid off.
每天我免费为你工作直到我偿清贷款
That's not working for free. That's paying off a debt.
那不是免费工作. 那是为了还贷工作
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
As a Christian, I'm doing you a favor.
作为基督徒，我帮你个忙
See, God don't give charity to those who are well and able.
看，上帝不会给那些健全的人施舍
You need to come up with this money on your own. OK?
你得自己想办法弄到钱.好吗？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
You'll thank me one day.
迟早有一天你会感谢我的
You cooking white food, you taste it with a different spoon.
你为白人做饭时要用不同的勺子品尝
If they see you put the tasting spoon back in the pot,
如果他们看到你把你的勺子留在罐里
might as well throw it all out.
就会把菜全部扔掉
Spoon, too.
勺子也是
And you use the same cup, same fork, same plate every day.
每天你都用同一个杯子，同一把叉子，同一个盘子
And you put it up in the cabinet.
你把它们收进橱柜
You tell that white woman that's where you're gonna keep it from now on out.
然后告诉白人妇女你都放哪了
Don't do it and see what happens.
你不这样做后果会很惨
Morning, ladies.
早安，女士们
When you're sewing white folks coffee,
你为白人煮好咖啡后
set it down in front of them.
要放到他们身前
Don't hand it to them, 'cause your hands can't touch.
你不能递给他们，因为你的手不能碰到杯子
And don't hit on they children.
还有千万不能打他们的孩子
White folks like to do they own spanking.
打屁股的事白人喜欢自己动手
And last thing. Come here.
最后一件事. 过来
Look at me.
看着我
No Sass-mouthing.
不得顶嘴
I mean it.
我是认真的
Give your mama a kiss.
让妈妈亲一下
Leroy had made Sugar quit school to help him with the bills.
Leroy让Sugar辍学帮他维持生计
And every day Minny went without a job,
每天Minny却不能工作
might have been a day Leroy took her from our world.
也许有一天Leroy会把她带离我们的世界
Good morning, everybody.
早上好，大家
But I knew.
但是我知道
I knew the only white lady Miss Hilly hadn't gotten to with her lies.
我知道有一个白人妇女没听过Hilly小姐那些谎话
Hey!
嗨！
Come on!
快点！
No sass-mouthing, Minny Jackson. No Sass-mouthing.
不要顶嘴，Minny Jackson，不要顶嘴
Aibileen said you'd be on time.
Aibileen说你会准时到
I'm Celia Rae Foote.
我叫Celia Rae Foote
I'm Minny Jackson.
我叫Minny Jackson
You, uh... cooking something?
你...刚在做饭吗？
One of those upside-down cakes from a magazine.
杂志上那些乱七八糟的蛋糕
It ain't working out too good. Come on, let's get you a cold Coca-Cola.
结果没做好，快，先给你拿个可乐.
Come on.
快
This here is the kitchen.
这是厨房
What in the hell?
这都什么乱七八糟
I guess I got some learning to do.
看来我有得学了
You sure do.
是有得学
Johnny's grandmama left him this house when she died.
Johnny的奶奶死后留给他这座房子
And then Johnny's mama wouldn't let me change a thing.
Johnny的妈妈要我保持原样
But if I had it my way,
但如果按照我的想法
this place would be wall-to-wall white carpet with gold trim.
这里该铺满镶带金边的地毯
None of this old stuff.
这些老古董全都扔掉
The main house has five beds and baths,
主房有5张床和卫生间
and then the pool house has two more beds and baths.
泳池边的房子还有2张床和卫生间
When y'all gonna start having some children,
你们打算何时要小孩
filling up all these empty beds?
来塞满这么些空床？
- I'm pregnant now. - Oh.
-我怀孕了 -哦
Gonna be eating for two. That's double the cooking.
那你要吃两人份. 做饭得要加倍
I know. It's an awful lotto do.
我明白，工作量很大
Five other maids have already turned me down.
其他五个女仆都拒绝了我
Let me at least get you some bus money.
我至少先给你些车费吧
Now, uh... when did you hear me say I don't want to clean this house?
...你是何时听到我不接手这房子的？
Wait. So you'll do it?
啊.那你愿意干了？
Ooh. No hugging. No hugging.
哦.别抱了.别抱了
I'm sorry. This is the first time I've hired a maid.
抱歉，这是我第一次雇到女仆
Come on.
快
- You hungry? - No, ma'am. Hold on a minute.
-你饿了吗？ -不，夫人.先等等
We gots to talk about some things first.
有一些事我们先要说清楚
Oh.
哦
I work Sunday through Friday.
我从周日到周五工作
No, you can't work at all on the weekends.
不，周末你不用工作
OK. What time you want me here?
好.那你想我几点来？
After 9:00, and you gotta leave before 4:00.
上午九点以后 下午四点以前
OK.
好
Now...
现在...
What your husband say you can pay?
你丈夫说你能付多少钱？
Johnny doesn't know I'm bringing in help.
Johnny不知道我有雇佣帮手
And what Mr. Johnny gonna do when he come home
那他回到家后会怎么做
and find a colored woman in his house?
发现一个黑女人在他房里？
It's not like I'd be fibbing.
不是我要撒谎
I just want him to think I can do this on my own.
我只想让他以为这些都是我一个人干的
I really need a maid.
我真的需要一个女仆
I'll be here tomorrow morning about 9:15.
明早9:15我会到这
Great.
好极了
- Miss Celia? - Hmm?
-Celia小姐？ -嗯？
I think you done burned up your cake.
你的蛋糕好像烤焦了
Doggone it!
该死！
OK let's see. What's Hrst up on the agenda?
好，看看，日程上第一项是什么？
We are running behind on our coat drive. Hurry up and clean out those closets.
衣服募捐活动有点滞后.我们得赶紧清理一下衣橱
But our Christmas benefit, however, is right on schedule. Mary Beth?
但是圣诞义卖就在眼前，Mary Beth?
Well, thanks to y'all, I can announce that we already filled
感谢大家，我宣布我们的
every raffle slot for baked goods!
杂物架已经装满食物！
Think we can put a dent in African children's hunger this year?
我们会很好的帮助解决非洲儿童饥饿问题
A big dent!
绝对的！
Now...
现在...
...I just found out the surgeon general
...我刚收到卫生局局长的回复
has reviewed the Home Health Sanitation Initiative that I drafted,
关于我起草的家庭健康与环境卫生的倡议
and he passed it along to Governor Barnett!
他已经将倡议转交给州长Barnett！
Skeeter, when can we expect to see the initiative in the newsletter?
Skeeter,我们何时能在时事通讯中看到这份倡议？
I gave it to you a month ago.
一个月前我就交给你了
I gave that to you myself.
我亲自交给你的
Would you please stand, Skeeter?
你能站起来吗，Skeeter?
I'll have it in there real soon.
我马上着手去办
Great.
好
- Sorry I'm late. - Hey.
-抱歉，我迟了 -嗨
Thanks.
谢谢
Hilly, I really am sorry about the newsletter.
Hilly,关于时事通讯的事我很抱歉
It's just with Mama being sick and all.
因为老妈生病的事
Oh, it's fine.
哦，没关系
I made you the egg and olive on rye, Miss Skeeter.
鸡蛋和橄榄加面包，Skeeter小姐
Oh, thank you, Henry.
哦，谢谢，Henry
You remembered.
你还记得
You're welcome.
不客气
Oh, Hilly, tell her. I can hardly stand it.
哦，Hilly，告诉她，我忍不住了
He's coming.
他来了
Oh, Skeeter, Stuart's definitely coming this time. Next Saturday week.
哦，Skeeter，Stuart这次一定会出现，就在下周六
Well, he's canceled twice before. Don't you think maybe that's a sign?
这个，他已经爽约两次. 你不认为这是暗示什么的吗？
Don't you dare say that.
快别这样说
You know I'm not gonna be his type.
你知道我不是他的菜
Damn it, Skeeter, I'm not gonna let you miss out on this
该死，Skeeter，这次我绝不会让你错过
because your mother convinced you you're not good enough for somebody like him.
不管你妈妈让你相信你配不上他这样优秀的男人
Saturday night.
周六晚
Good morning.
早
Good morning, Baby Girl.
早，宝贝
Good morning.
早
I reckon I'm ready to talk about Miss Leefolt now.
我想我已经准备好谈论下Leefolt小姐了
Baby Girl still gotta wear a diaper when she sleep at night.
晚上小女孩还是穿着尿布睡觉
And it don't get changed till I get there in the morning.
没人会去换尿布直到我上午到那
That about ten hours she gotta sleep in her mess.
十个小时她都和她的便便睡在一起
Now Miss Leefolt pregnant with her second baby.
现在Leefolt小姐怀了第二胎
Lord... I pray this child turn out good.
主啊...我祈祷这孩子能长大成人
It's a lonely road if a mama don't think their child is pretty.
这是条孤单的道路如果妈妈认为她的孩子不够漂亮
That's very true.
深有感触
Miss Leefolt should not be having babies.
Leefolt小姐就不该要孩子
Write that down.
把这句话记下
Treelore would like me doing this.
Treelore会希望我这样做的
He always said we were gonna have a writer in the family one day.
他总说家里迟早有一天会出个作家
I always thought it was gonna be him. Maybe it's gonna be me.
我原想那人准是他，看来也许是我
Aibileen, Aibileen.
They done set a bomb off in Medgar Evers' carport.
他们在Medgar Evers车库里引爆了炸弹
Yule Mae told me what y'all was up to. I didn't want to believe it.
Yule Mae告诉我你正在做的事，我简直不敢相信
And just what makes you think colored people need your help?
是什么让你以为有色人种需要你的帮助？
- Why do you care? - Minny.
-你为什么会关心？ -Minny
Maybe you just want to get Aibileen in trouble.
也许你只想让Aibileen陷入麻烦吧
No.
不是
I want to show her perspective.
我想展示她的看法
So people might understand what it's like from your side.
这样人们也许就会明白你们的感受
Well, it's a real Fourth of July picnic.
是啊，这就是我们的梦想
It's what we dream of doing all weekend long.
我们周末就梦想着这样干
Get back into they house, polish the silver.
回到他们家，擦亮银器
And we just love not making minimum wage or getting Social Security.
能拿到不是最低的工资和社保 我们真是幸运
And how we love they children when they little.
孩子小的时候我们真好喜欢
And then they turn out just like they mamas.
结果孩子长大后就和妈妈一个样
I know.
我知道
Maybe things can change.
也许事情会有所改变
What Iaw's gonna say you gotta be nice to your maid?
谁跟你说要对女仆好的？
You don't have to do this now, Minny.
你不必这个样，Minny
You damn right I don't!
太对了我不该这样
You two give me the heart palpitations.
你俩真让我心寒
And that's a good mood.
她这算心情好的了
All right. I'm gonna do it.
好的. 我来吧
But I need to make sure she understands this ain't no game we playing here.
但是我要确保她明白我们不是在玩游戏
Slide your chair out from under that table. Face me.
把椅子挪出来，面对我
I need to see you square on at all times.
我要确保你一直端端正正的面对我
I gotta come up with your questions, too?
你不是要问我问题吗？
Oh.
哦
Uh, let's begin with where you were born.
从你在哪出生开始吧
Belzoni, Mississippi, on my great-auntie's sofa.
Belzoni，密西西比，在我曾伯母的沙发上
Next.
下一个
- I put the green beans in first. - OK.
-我先放进绿豆 -好的
Then I get on the pork chops so I can get started on that cornbread.
然后把猪肉切好 接着开始弄玉米面包
Once Minny got to talking about food, she liked to never stop.
一旦Minny谈起食物，她就滔滔不绝
And when she got to talking about the white ladies, it took all night.
而当她谈起白人小姐，这晚就没完了
Then she say, "Oh, Minny, I'm gonna give you a paid vacation."
然后她说，“哦，Minny，我会给你一个带薪假期”
I ain't never had no paid vacation in my life.
这辈子我从没有过带薪假期
A week later I come back, and they done moved to Mobile.
一周后我回来时，他们已经搬家去了Mobile
Miss Lazy Fingers scared I'd find a new job before she moved.
懒指头小姐害怕我在她搬家前找到新工作
Ain't that right, Aibileen?
对吧，Aibileen？
We gots to get some more maids.
我们得再去找些女仆
It hard. You go try and see.
很难.你尽管去试试
OK, I will.
好，我会去的
We gone and done it now.
我们赶紧了结这事吧
Skeeter! Get down here! Something just arrived from New York for you.
Skeeter！快下来！有东西刚从纽约寄来给你
What is that?
是什么？
The Shinalator. All the way from New York City.
烫发机.从纽约寄来的
I'm a good mother.Come on. Sit down.
我是个好母亲，快，坐下
The whole system cost 11 dollars.Even smells expensive.
整套机器可花了11美元，闻起来都是钱味
You're gonna look beautiful on your date tonight.
今晚约会你一定美极了！
I can feel the hope in your fingers.
你的一触一碰让我芙蓉初发
Holy shit.
我去
- You shrunk five inches. - Oh, my God.
-你稍矮了5英寸 -哦，我的天
You'll be able to wear heels tonight.
今晚你得穿上高跟鞋
You're not leaving the house in those awful Mexican man shoes.
穿着那些墨西哥鞋可不准你离开
Can I take the Cadillac?
我能开车去吗？
We promised the Cadillac to Carlton and Rebecca tonight,
我们答应今晚把车借给Carlton和Rebecca
so William's cousin will just have to come pick you up himself.
这样William的表兄就得亲自上门接你
- I'll take the truck. - it's hooked up to the motor grader.
-那我开卡车 -它和平地机连在一起
I'll drive slow.
我会慢慢开
Skeeter! Skeeter!
Now remember, no gentleman wants to spend the evening with a sourpuss.
记住，没有人想和讨厌鬼呆一晚上
Don't mope! Smile!
别没精打采！要微笑！
And for heaven's sakes, don't sit like some squaw Indian! Cross your ankles!
还有坐姿别大咧咧的，要叉腿！
I love you!
爱你！
Stuart, she'll be here any minute.
Stuart，她马上就到
-Hi
-嗨
Skeeter.
Boys, we'll be right back. Y'all talk about quarterbacks or something.
我们马上回来.你们先聊聊四分卫什么的
Yule Mae, get Miss Skeeter a Coca-Cola.
Yule Mae，给Skeeter小姐拿个可乐
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
Want a drink?
喝一杯？
Just water, please.
水就好
Double Old Kentucky, straight with a water back. Make that two backs.
一杯双份波本威士忌不加水，两杯不加水
You sure you don't want to just make it the whole bottle and a straw?
你干脆整瓶打开插吸管喝好了
Honey, there's the lieutenant governor. Let's go say hi.
亲爱的，那是州长助理，我们过去打个招呼
Good to see you, sir. You remember my wife?
见到您真高兴，先生. 还记得我妻子吗？
Hi, how are you? Good to see you.
嗨，你好，见到你很高兴
So, what do you do with your time?
平常你都干些什么？
You work?
你工作吗？
I write.
我写作
But right now I'm working on a domestic maintenance column
现在专职于一个家庭生活专栏
for The Jackson Journal.
为Jackson日报
You mean housekeeping.
你是指家政管理吧
Jesus, I can't think of anything worse than reading a cleaning column,
上帝，还有比读清洁专栏更糟的事吗
except for maybe writing one.
那就是自己动手写
Well, I can.
这我知道
Working with a bunch of greasy, stinky men in the middle of the ocean.
最糟就是在大海上和一群油腻发臭的男人工作
It sounds like a ploy to find a husband, becoming an expert in keeping house.
在成为家政女王的同时找男人看来是个不错的消遣
Well, aren't you a genius? You figured out my whole scheme.
你真聪明，完全被你看穿了
Isn't that what all you girls from Ole Miss major in...
你们这些从Ole Miss毕业的女孩...
...professional husband hunting?
...专业不就是找男人吗？
Who is hungry?
谁饿了？
I'm sorry, but were you dropped on your head as an infant?
抱歉，你婴儿时被摔坏脑子了吧？
Or were you just born stupid?
还是你天生就愚蠢？
So, what can you cook?
你都会烹饪什么？
Oh, um, I can cook cornpone.
哦，我会做玉米饼
Boil potatoes.
炖土豆
I can do grits.
做玉米粉
Well...
这个
...I reckon if there's anything you ought to know about cooking, it's this.
我想烹饪方面你必须知道的一件事就是这个
The most important invention since they put mayonnaise in a jar.
自把蛋黄酱装进罐子后最重要的发明
- You got gum in your hair,
头发里粘了口香糖
you got a squeaky door hinge...
门铰链吱吱响...
Crisco.
Crisco（一个植物油的牌子)
How pretty.
真漂亮
Looks like frosting.
就像雪霜
You got bags under your eyes.
眼睛下有眼袋
Want to soften your husband's scaly feet.
想要放松丈夫的双脚
Mm-hm. Crisco.
嗯哼. Crisco
But it's best for frying chicken.
但最好的用处是炸鸡腿
Frying chicken just...
炸鸡腿...
...tend to make you feel better about life.
...会让你感觉世间如此美妙
At least me, anyway.
至少对我是这样
Mm, I love me some fried chicken.
我爱死炸鸡腿了
Now...
现在...
...shake that.
...摇一摇
Oh.
哦
This is so much fun!
这真有趣！
All right, all right. The chicken already dead, Miss Celia.
好了，小鸡已经死透了，Celia小姐
Yep. He dead.
是的，死绝了
There you are.
你在这呢
I'm starved. Looks so good.
饿死我了，看起来真好吃
We done been over this, Miss Celia.
我们已经说好了，Celia小姐
You supposed to eat in the dining room. That's how it works.
你该在餐厅用餐，事情就该这样
Let me take your plate back.
我帮你把盘子拿过去
I'm fine right here, Minny.
我在这里很好，Minny
What?
什么？
I just want you to know I'm real grateful you're here.
我就想让你知道你能在这我很感激
You gots plenty more to be grateful for than me.
你要感激的事不该是我
And look, now I ain't messing around no more.
看，趁现在事情还没变糟
Now Mr. Johnny gonna catch me here,
如果Johnny先生在这把我抓个正着
and shoot me dead right here on this no-wax floor.
一枪把我射死在这没打蜡的地板上
You gots to tell him.
你得告诉他
Ain't he wondering how the cooking's so good?
他不会好奇食物怎么突然可口起来？
You're right.
你说得对
Maybe we ought to burn the chicken a little.
也许我们该把鸡腿烤焦些
Minny don't burn chicken.
Minny从不烤焦鸡腿
I like this Sarah Ross. She testifies without complaining too much.
我喜欢Sarah Ross，她作证却不会抱怨太多
And that Bertha, she's got chutzpah, I'll give her that.
至于Bertha，她就是一个厚脸皮
So you liked it?
所以你喜欢这故事？
Eugenia, Martin Luther King just invited
Eugenia，马丁・路德・金 在八月
the entire country to march with him in D.C. in August.
刚邀请整个国家和他一起游行
This many Negroes and whites
这么多黑鬼和白人
have not worked together since Gone with the Wind.
自从《乱世佳人》以来就没一起工作过
How many stories have you recorded thus far?
到现在你收录了多少故事？
The ones you've read.
就你现在读到的这些
Two domestics, that's all?
两个仆人，这就是全部？
I'm real close to getting more interviews.
我马上就会有其他的采访
Don't send me anything else until you do have more maids.
先别给我发任何东西 直到你找到更多女仆
Yes, ma'am. How... how many more?
好，那...多少才算多？
I don't know. At least a dozen.
我不知道，至少一打
My advice to you is to write it and write it fast
我的建议是你赶紧写，抓紧写
before this whole civil rights thing blows over.
在这整个民权活动结束以前
Now good night to you, Miss Phelan.
现在该说晚安了，Phelan小姐
We need a dozen more.
我们还需要一打女仆
Me and Aibileen done asked everybody we know. Thirty-one maids.
我和Aibileen问过认识的每个人，31个女仆
They all too scared. Think we crazy.
她们都吓坏了，认为我们疯了
If we don't get more, we're not getting published.
如果找不到更多女仆，就没法出版发行
I gots plenty stories, Miss Skeeter.
我有很多故事，Skeeter小姐
Just write them down and invent the maid that said it.
记下它们然后捏造一个女仆来复述
You're already making up names. Just make up the maids, too.
你已经捏造了名字，连女仆一起捏造算了
We're not gonna do that. That would be wrong.
我们不能那样做，那样是不对的
Don't give up on this, Miss Skeeter.
别轻言放弃，Skeeter小姐
It wouldn't be real.
那样就不真实了
They Killed my son.
他们杀死我儿子
He fell carrying two-by-fours at the mill.
他在磨坊被车撞倒
Truck run over him, crushed his lung.
卡车碾过他，压碎他的肺
Aibileen
That white foreman threw his body on back of a truck.
白人工头把他的尸体扔上卡车
Drove to the colored hospital...
开车到黑人医院...
...dumped him there and honked the horn.
...把他扔在那，然后按了下喇叭
There was nothing they could do, so I brought my baby home.
医生无能为力，我只好把他带回家
Laid him down on that sofa right there.
他就躺在那沙发上
He died right in front of me.
他就死在我身前
He was just 24 years old, Miss Skeeter. Best part of a person's life.
他刚24岁，Skeeter小姐，正值青春年华
Anniversary of his death comes...
每年他的忌日之际...
...every year, and I can't breathe.
...每年，我都无法呼吸
But to y'all, it's just another day of bridge.
对你们来说，那只是桥牌度日的另一天
You stop this...
你放弃的话...
...everything I wrote, he wrote, everything he was is gonna die with him.
...我写的，他写的每一件事都将随他逝去
I am just honored to be hosting Elizabeth's shower.
我很荣幸能为Elizabeth主持这次送礼会
Doesn't she look glowing, everybody?
她看起来真是美极了，对吧？
- Yes, she does!
-是，她光彩照人
Honey, you hold on to it, to the bitter end.
亲爱的，苦日子等着你，你要坚持住
- I'll try. - Well, congratulations.
-我会努力的 -不错，恭喜你
I'm hungry, Mommy.
我饿了，妈妈
She's always hungry.
她没完没了的饿
You know she can hear you, Elizabeth.
你知道她听得到你，Elizabeth
I'll cut you a piece of cake, baby. Go on, now.
我去帮你切块蛋糕，来
Aibileen, are you enjoying your new bathroom over at Elizabeth's?
Aibileen, Elizabeth那的新卫生间你还喜欢吧
Nice to have your own. isn't it, Aibileen?
拥有自己的卫生间很棒吧，Aibileen？
Yes, ma'am. And I thank you.
是的，夫人，我感谢你
Separate, but equal.
单独的，但是平等
That's what Ross Barnett says, and you can't argue with the governor.
Ross Barnett就这样说，你可不能反驳州长
Well, certainly not in Mississippi,the birthplace of modern-day government.
当然不能，密西西比可是现代政府的发扬地
Hey, Miss Skeeter. Can I get you something?
嗨，Skeeter小姐，想吃点什么？
No, thanks.
不用，谢谢
Yule Mae, I wanted to talk to you about something.
Yule Mae，我想和你谈点事情
I already know what you're gonna ask, Miss Skeeter.
我知道你要问什么，Skeeter小姐
Minny and Aibileen already did.
Minny和Aibileen已经问过了
I'm trying to get my boys off to college.
我正在想办法送孩子们上大学
It's worthwhile what y'all are doing, but...
你们的所作所为值得付出，但是...
...but my boys are worth more.
...但我的孩子们更重要
I understand.
我明白
What do you understand, Skeeter?
你明白什么，Skeeter？
Yule Mae was just saying how excited she is that her boys are going to college.
Yule Mae正说她很兴奋 她就要送孩子去上大学了
Did you also ask Miss Skeeter if you could borrow money?
你向Skeeter小姐借钱了吧？
Of course not.
当然没有
I'm gonna put Billy down for his nap.
我去哄Billy睡觉
Excuse me.
抱歉
Come on, baby.
来，宝贝
Skeeter, are you intentionally not putting my initiative in the newsletter?
Skeeter，你是故意不把我的倡议放进时事通讯里吧？
No, not at all. I just have been really busy with Mama.
没有，我就是在忙老妈的事
I know.
明白
I know, you must be so worried about your mother, but...
我明白你很担心你老妈，但...
I'm worried about you.
我更担心你
Reading this stuff?
你还看这些玩意儿？
Believe it or not, there are real racists in this town.
爱信不信，镇里活跃着种族主义分子
If the wrong person caught you with anything like that,
如果某个坏人发现你这些东西
you'd be in serious trouble.
你可就陷入大麻烦了
I'll be on the lookout.
我会小心的
Put my initiative in the newsletter.
把我的倡议放进时事通讯
OK?
好吗？
Skeeter, get up!
Skeeter，快起来！
- No! What? - We've got to get dressed.
-什么事？ -我们得打扮一下
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Don't panic. Don't panic.
别慌，别慌
There's a particularly tall and very handsome man named Stuart here for you.
有个高大英俊的 叫Stuart的男人找你
Oh, God.
哦，天
Oh, mother.
哦，妈妈
You would not like him. Trust me.
你不会喜欢他的，相信我
He's a drunken asshole.
他就是个酒鬼
Love and hate are two horns on the same goat, Eugenia, and you need a goat.
爱恨就像硬币的正反面，Eugenia，你正需要个硬币
Put that on. Hurry!
快穿上这衣服
Look, I know it was a few weeks back,
我知道已经过去好几周
but I came to say I'm sorry for the way I acted.
我来就是为我上次的表现而道歉
Who sent you, William or Hilly?
谁让你来的，William还是Hilly？
Neither.
都不是
Hilly. But I wanted to come, OK.
是Hily，但我自己也想来
I was rude, and I've been thinking about it a lot.
我那样很无礼，我也一直在考虑
- Well, I haven't. So you can just go. - Goddamn it!
-我可没有，你可以走了 -该死！
I told Hilly I wasn't ready to go out on any date. Wasn't even close to ready.
我告诉Hily我还没准备好开始约会，根本没有
I was engaged last year. She ended it.
去年我订婚了，她反悔了
I'm sure she did.
我相信她会的
It's not like that. I'm not always a jerk.
不是这样，我并不总是混蛋
We had been dating since we were 15, and you know how it is.
我们从15岁就在一起，你明白那意味着什么
Actually, I don't. I've never really dated anyone before.
事实上，我不明白，之前我从没约会过
Ever?
从没？
Ever.
从来没有
All right, I, uh...
那好，我...
Well, that must be it, then.
原来是这样
- What? - You, Skeeter.
-什么？ -你，Skeeter
I've never met a woman that says exactly what she's thinking.
我从没遇到过像你一样直言的女人
- Well, I got plenty to say. - Yeah, I'll bet you do.
-我要说的可多了 -我相信
You make me laugh, smile.
你让我开心，微笑
Would you like to come have dinner with me?
一起吃晚饭吧？
We could talk. I could actually listen to you this time.
我们好好谈谈，这次我认真听
I can't think of anything worse.
我看这主意糟透了
I understand, and I'm sorry.
我明白，抱歉
That's what I came here to say, and I said it.
我来就是说抱歉的，现在我说过了
Just give me a minute.
等我一会儿
Let me get my sweater.
我去拿上毛衣
Not a big fan of oysters, huh?
对牡蛎不感兴趣？
Oysters are a vehicle for crackers and ketchup.
牡蛎带的病毒可多了
Well, here's to new beginnings.
敬崭新的开始
Mm.
嗯
You're disgusting.
你真恶心
You've already made that pretty clear.
从你的表情感觉得到
And just so you know, the boys caught me reading
你知道吗，小子们抓个我正着
your Miss Myrna column on the rig the other day.
一天就在我看你写的Myrna小姐专栏时
Really? You read them?
真的？你有看？
All of them.
全部
Very informative, too.
很有教育意义
I had no idea that ground egg shells got grease out of clothes.
以前从不知道蛋壳可以去污
Well, I do my homework.
我可是做足了功课
You're a good writer, Skeeter.
你是个优秀的作者，Skeeter
Thank you.
谢谢
I want to be a journalist.
我想当一名记者
Or maybe a novelist. Or maybe both.
或者小说家，也许两者都作
I like that.
我喜欢
You're really smart. And pretty.
你很聪明也很漂亮
Skeeter.
I hope you get to write something really good.
真心希望你能写出好东西
Something you believe in.
写下你所坚信的
Hello?
你好？
- What? I'm coming!
-什么？我就来！
Aibileenl Come on. We have to go help Hilly. Right now!
Aibileen！快，我们要去给Hily帮忙，立刻马上
- Oh! You're trespassing!
-你这是非法侵入！
- It's Skeeter!
是Skeeter！
She put it in the newsletter.
时事通讯的事是她干的
Oh, my God.
我的天
I specifically said, "Drop old coats at my house."
我特意嘱咐“把老旧衣服放到我家”
- Not commodes!
-不是马桶！
Why would she do this to me?
她为什么这样对我？
I don't know. I don't Know, Hilly.
我不知道，我不知道，Hily
It's so embarrassing.
真是丢脸
Oh, Lord.
哦，上帝
I go potty, Mommy.
我要便便，妈妈
No! Mae Mobley!
不要！Mae Mobley!
You get off of that toilet!
快从那马桶上下来！
- You will catch diseases, you hear me? - Mommy!
-你会得病的，听到没？ -妈妈
You will catch diseases on those toilets.
坐那些马桶会让你得病的
You is kind, you is smart,
你很善良，你很聪明
you is important.
你很重要
Don't shop for anything on Capitol Street.
不要在Capitol街上购物
Let's let the merchants down on Capitol Street feel the economic pinch.
让Capitol街的商户们喝西北风去吧
Let me say this to you.
让我这样跟你说
I had one merchant to call me, and he said,
一个商人打电话给我，他说
"l want you to know that I've talked to my national ofHoe today,
“我要你知道今天我已经和全国代表谈过了
and they want me to tell you that we don't need nigger business."
他们要我转告你 我们不需要赚黑人的钱”
These are stores that help to support the White Citizens' Council,
这些商店公开支持白人市民议会
the council that is dedicated to keeping you and I second-class citizens.
这个议会想方设法让你我成为二等公民
Mama!
妈妈！
Don't encourage them like that.
别鼓励他们这样做
- That is national news. - I won't have it!
-这是国家新闻 -我不允许
You understand?
你明白吗？
How you doing, Miss Clark?
你好吗，Clark女士
All right, Henry.
我很好，Henry
Thank you. How you doing?
谢谢，你好吗？
If God is willing, Miss Clark. If God is willing.
愿上帝与我同在，Clark小姐，愿上帝与我同在
That's good.
那不错
- Yeah. - That's good.
-是 -不错
What's going on out there, mister?
外面发生了什么事，先生？
Colored people off.
黑人下车
The rest of you, let me know where you're going.
其余的人告诉我你的目的地
I'll get you close as I can.
我会尽量送你一程
What happened?
发生了什么？
I don't know. Some nigger got shot.
不知道，有黑鬼被枪杀
- Where you headed? - Woodrow Wilson.
-你去哪？ -Woodrow Wilson
Woodrow Wilson. All right.
Woodrow Wilson，好
- You gonna be all right, Miss Clark? - I'll be all right. You go on now.
-你一人没事吧，Clark小姐？ -我没事，你去吧
- You want me to walk you? - No, thank you. I'll be all right.
-要不我送你？ -不用，谢谢，我能行
You have a good night.
晚安
Which way you going?
你往哪边走？
We View this as a cold,
我们看到的是一场
- brutal, deliberate...
冷血，残忍，精心策划...
...killing in a savage, uncivilized state.
...的屠杀，在这个野蛮不开化的州
There is no state with a record that approaches that of Mississippi
没有哪一个州像密西西比这样
in inhumanity murden brutality
被残暴的谋杀
- and racial hatred.
和种族仇恨笼罩
It is absolutely at the bottom of the list.
这个州绝对是国家最黑暗的一个
Fifteen minutes past midnight,
凌晨十二点15分
Evers got out of his car beside his home in a Negro residential area.
黑人住宅区内 Evers在他家附近下车
In a vacant lot about 40 yards away
就在40米开外的空旷地带
a sniper fired a single shot from a high-powered rifle at Evers' silhouette.
一个狙击手朝Evers开了一枪
I'm all right. Sit down. You all right?
我没事，坐下，你还好吗？
- I'm OK. - The bullet hit him in the back,
-我没事 -子弹打中他后背
crashed through his body through a window into the house.
穿过他的身子和玻璃飞进屋内
He died within an hour at a Jackson hospital.
一小时内他死于Jackson医院
City detectives believe the fatal shot was fired from...
市警探认为致命的一枪来自...
KKK shot him. An hour ago.
三K党射杀了他，一小时之前
Right in front of his children, Aibileen.
当着他孩子的面，Aibileen
We're gonna pray for the Evers. We're gonna pray for IllIyrlie.
让我们一起为Evers祈祷
We living in hell. Trapped.
我们活在地狱里，被困
Our kids, trapped.
我们的孩子也是
Sugar, take your brothers and sisters and y'all go on to bed.
Sugar，带你的兄弟姐妹去上床睡觉
Good night.
晚安
Good night. Good night.
晚安，晚安
Oh. Good night, baby.
晚安，宝贝
What they gonna do if they catch us with Miss Skeeter?
他们会怎么做，如果发现我们和Skeeter小姐在做的事
We're gonna be careful.
我们会小心的
Hitch us to a pickup? Drag us behind? Shoot me in front of my children?
把我们拖在车后？拉我们到后院？当着孩子的面爆我头？
We ain't doing civil rights.
我们没参与民权活动
We're just telling stories like they really happened.
我们只是讲述真实发生的事
- You're a fool, old woman.
-你真傻，老女人
A fool.
傻瓜一个
Miss Phelan, the presses are heating up. We needed Miss Myrna 30 minutes ago.
Phelan小姐，马上就要出版了，赶紧把Myrna小姐的专栏搞定
Yes, Sir.
是的，先生
Chop-chop.
速度
Good Lord.
天啊
Miss Celia?
Celia小姐？
Go home. I'll see you tomorrow.
回家去吧，明天见
You mess up your hair coloring again?
你不会又把头发搞坏了吧？
I helped you ix it last time. We got it back to butter batch.
上次我重新帮你弄好了
Was real pretty, remember?
很漂亮，记得吗？
Miss Celia.
Celia小姐
I told you, go home!
我叫你回家！
I said get out!
我说出去！
Why is there so much blood?
怎么会流这么多血？
Next one's gonna catch, Miss Celia. You just wait and see.
你还会怀上的，Celia小姐，等着瞧吧
We got married 'cause I was pregnant.
我们结婚是因为我怀孕了
Then I lost it a month later.
但一个月后孩子没了
Johnny wants kids now.
Johnny想要个孩子
What's he gonna do with me?
他会怎么对我？
Well...
这...
Mr. Johnny just gonna have to get over it.
Johnny先生自会想办法的
He doesn't know about the baby.
这孩子他根本不知道有
Or the two before.
之前的两个也是
Yule Mae Davis?
- What do you want me to do? - You're under arrest.
-你想干什么？ -你被捕了
Just call my husband. Just call my husband.
打电话给我丈夫,打电话给我丈夫
- Wait a minute. I want my purse. - No, you're under arrest.
-等等，我拿下钱包 -不行，你被捕了
I want to get my purse. I want to get my purse! Aibee!
我要钱包！我要钱包！Aibee！
- Don't fight, Yule Mae! - Aibee!
-别反抗，Yule Mae! -Aibee！
Aibee, I want my purse! I want my purse!
Aibee，我要钱包！我要钱包！
Just let me go!
放开我！
Yule Mae, don't fight.
Yule Mae，别反抗
I knew she was a thief the day she started.
打一开始我就知道她是个贼
A nigra walks into a pawn shop with a ring of such size and color.
一个黑鬼拿着这样一个款式的戒指去了当铺
It took them all of ten minutes to find out where she worked.
不用十分钟他们就查出她在哪工作
I am desperate for a grilled cheese sandwich.
我要乳酪三明治
Are you? Are you? Do you want a grilled cheese sandwich?
你呢？你呢？你要吃乳酪三明治吗？
- Oh, yes.
哦，好
Just go sit down over there.
先去那边坐
Miss Skeeter, you best head on over to Miss Aibileen's house.
Skeeter小姐，你最好去Aibileen小姐家一趟
Now.
现在
I'm gonna help with your stories.
你的书我会帮你
I'm gonna help, too. Mm-hm.
我也会
We all are.
我们都会
-That's right. - I'll help you.
-对 -我会帮你
I used to take a shortcut every day
过去我每天都会绕近路
when I went to work at Dr. Dixon's house.
去Dixon医生那工作
Cut through that farmer's lower 40 to get there.
穿过农场走40码就到
One day this farmer was waiting for me with a gun.
一天农场主拿枪在那等着我
Said he'd shoot me dead if I walked on his land again.
说如果我再经过他的农场他就开枪打死我
Dr. Dixon went and paid that farmer double for two of those acres.
Dixon医生为那片地付了双倍的钱
Told him he was gonna start farming, too.
告诉他 他也打算种地
But he bought that just for me, so I could get to work easy.
其实他是为了我方便走才买下那地
He did.
就是这样
I worked for Miss Jolene's mother till the day she died.
我为Jolene小姐的母亲工作直到她去世
Then her daughter, Miss Nancy, asked me to come and work for her.
接着她女儿Nancy小姐叫我去她家工作
Miss Nancy is a real sweet lady.
Nancy小姐人很不错
But Miss Jolene's ma done put it in her will I got to work for Miss Jolene.
但Jolene小姐的母亲遗嘱里把我留给了Jolene小姐
Miss Jolene's a mean woman.
Jolene小姐是个刻薄的女人
Mean for sport.
刻薄到骨子里
Lord, I tried to find another job.
天，我曾试着另找一份工作
But in everybody's mind
但在大家看来
the French family and Miss Jolene owned me.
French家和Jolene小姐拥有我
Owned me.
拥有我
I leave early this week for Thanksgiving.
感恩节到了 这礼拜我会先走
Our last editors' meeting is December 17th,
最近一个编辑会议在12月17号
so if you want a prayer of this getting read,
如果你想让人看的话
- I'd better have it by then. - That's in three weeks, Miss Stein.
-最好就等到那时吧 -那是在三礼拜后了，Stein小姐
Well, otherwise it goes in the pile.
否则它就会被搁置
You do not want it in the pile.
你不想被搁置吧
Yes, ma'am.
是的，女士
And put something personal in there. Write about the maid who raised you.
写点你自己的事，就写养育你的女仆
I understand.
明白
Well, we have a lot of work to do before the benefit, don't we?
义卖之前我们有很多工作要做，对吧？
I know, but I think We're on track. We're doing quite well.
我知道，但事情一切顺利，我们做得不错
- it's so good. - Mm-hm.
-真好吃 -嗯
- Who's there? - I don't know.
-是谁啊？ -不知道
Aibileen?
Hey, Elizabeth!
嗨，Elizabeth！
It's me, Celia Foote.
是我，Celia Foote
I was in the neighborhood. Thought I'd drop by.
我刚在附近，就想顺便拜访一下
Everybody hide. Everybody get down, get down.
大家都躲起来，蹲下，蹲下
Get down! Get down! Get down!
蹲下！蹲下！
- Turn off the music. - Who are we hiding from?
-关掉音乐 -我们这是在躲谁啊？
- Shh!
嘘！
- Hey!
嗨！
Shh!
嘘！
I brought a chocolate pie!
我带了巧克力派！
My maid, Minny, made it.
我的女仆，Minny做的
She's in the bushes.
她站在灌木丛里
Don't be taking those women any more pies, you understand?
不要再给那些女人带任何派，明白吗？
They made me stand there like I was the vacuum salesman.
她们就让我站在那，好像我是吸尘器推销员
Why, Minny?
为什么，Minny？
Because they know about you getting knocked up by Mr. Johnny.
因为你遇到了Johnny先生
Mad you married one of their mens.
她们恨你抢走了她们的男人
And especially since Miss Hilly and Mr. Johnny had just broke up, too.
尤其是Hily小姐刚和Johnny先生分手不久
Hilly probably thinks that I was fooling around with Johnny
Hily也许认为以前是我在勾搭Johnny
when they were still going steady.
当他们感情还平稳的时候
Mm-hm.
嗯
And Missus Walters always said Miss Hilly still sweet on Mr. Johnny, too.
Walters太太说Hily小姐对Johnny还有感觉
No wonder!
怪不得！
They don't hate me. They hate what they think I did.
他们恨的不是我，恨的是我的作为
They hate you 'cause they think you white trash.
他们恨你是因为他们认为你是垃圾
I'm just going to have to tell Hilly I ain't no boyfriend stealer.
我要去告诉Hily我不是挖墙脚的人
In fact, I'll tell her Friday night at the benefit.
这周五晚义卖会上我就去告诉她
You don't need to be going to that benefit, Miss Celia.
你不必去那义卖会，Celia小姐
Did you hear me? You just stay home.
听到了吗？你就呆在家里
That looks bad.
你样子不好
Let me take a look.
让我看看
I got to get these peas on.
我得去把这些豌豆煮上
I know you didn't fall in no tub, Minny.
我知道你不是在浴盆里滑倒，Minny
You know what I'd do if I were you?
你知道我是你的话我会怎么做
I'd give it right back to him.
我会直接打回去
I'd hit him over the head with a skillet,
抡起锅来就照头砸
and I'd tell him, "Go straight to hell."
然后告诉他，“去死吧”
From here, the members of the family...
从这里出发，家庭成员...
...visitors from foreign countries and others
...还有外国的来宾
will walk to St. Matthew's Cathedral.
会一起走进Matthew's Cathedral大教堂
Senator Edward Kennedy getting out of the car.
现在下车的是Kennedy参议员
Mrs. Kennedy
Kennedy夫人
Robert Kennedy, Attorney General.
首席检察官Robert Kennedy
Sweetheart, I gotta get down to the coast.
甜心，我得回海上去
I'll be back in time for the benefit.
义卖之前我一定回来
The world done gone crazy, Miss Skeeter, and I'm scared.
整个世界都发疯了，Skeeter小姐，我好怕
What if people find out what we writing, figure out Niceville really Jackson
如果人们看了书之后发现Niceville实际就是Jackson
figure out who who?
发现谁是谁？
Maybe we need us some insurance.
也许我们需要点保障
I told God I'd never speak of it again.
我向上帝发誓不会再提那事
But we ain't got no choice.
但看来我别无选择
Sorry.
抱歉
I need to tell y'all about the terrible awful I done to Miss Hilly.
我得告诉你关于Hily小姐我干下的可怕之事
It might be the only thing that keep us safe.
只有这件事能确保我们的安全
Mmm.
嗯
Mm-mm-mm.
So...
那么...
Nobody wanted to hire a sass-mouthing, thieving nigra.
没人会雇一个爱顶嘴 偷盗的黑鬼
Did they?
对吧？
Oh. Pie's as good as always, Minny
哦，派一如既往的美味，Minny
I'm glad you like it.
很高兴你喜欢
Mmm.
嗯
Oh.
哦
If I take you back, I'll have to cut your pay five dollars a week.
如果要雇你回来，一周要减5美元
Take me back?
雇我回来？
What do you put in here that makes it taste so good?
你在里面都放了什么 这么好吃！
That good vanilla from Mexico...
来自墨西哥的香草...
...and something else real special.
...还有其他一些特别的东西
Mmm.
嗯
No, no, no, Missus Walters. That's Miss Hilly's special pie.
不，Walters太太，这是Hily小姐的特制派
Mama can have a piece.
妈妈也能吃一块
Cut her one.
切给她一块
Go get a plate.
去拿个盘子
Eat my shit.
吃我的屎吧
What'd you say?
你说什么？
I said, "Eat... my... shit."
我说“吃...我的...屎吧”
Have you lost your mind?
你发疯了吗？
No, ma'am, but you about to, 'cause you just did.
没有，女士，但你要疯了，因为你刚吃了
Did what?
吃了什么？
And you didn't eat just one.
你还不只吃了一块
- You had two slices!
你吃了两块！
Run, Minny, run!
快跑，Minny！
You trying to get yourself killed?
你是想送死吗？
No! I wasn't planning on telling.
没有！我本不打算说出来的
I just wanted to see her take a bite.
我只想看她吃一口
Then I was gonna leave. Be done with her forever.
然后我就离开，彻底和她了结
Before I knew it, I had done told that woman what was in that pie!
但不知不觉，我已经告诉那女人派里有什么了
I done ask God to forgive me.
我向上帝祈祷宽恕很多次了
But more for what happened to poor Miss Walters.
但更多是为了可怜的Walters太太祈祷
Miss Hilly threw her in that nursing home... just for laughing.
Hily小姐把她扔进了养老院...就因为她笑了！
We can't put that story in the book.
我们不能把这故事放进书里
We ain't got no choice.
我们别无选择
Hilly Holbrook can't let nobody know that pie story about her.
Hilly Holbrook不会让任何人知道派的事
Exactly. If people find out the terrible awful
的确，如果人们知道了你和Hily小姐
was you and Miss Hilly we in trouble there ain't words for.
之间这件事，我们就麻烦了
Right! But don't you see?
对！还不明白吗？
She gonna go to her grave convincing folks this book ain't about Jackson.
她到死都不会让人知道这些事发生在Jackson
Now, that keeps us safe. Insured.
这样我们我就安全了，确保无疑
No.
不
No, that's too dangerous.
不，这样太危险了
Y'all two brought me into this, but I'm gonna finish it.
是你俩拉我进这淌浑水的，但我会了结此事的
Either put it in, or pull my parts out altogether. Y'all pick!
把那故事放进去，还是把我放进停尸房，你们选吧！
Thank you, Tommy. I should be out by 10:00. See you then.
谢谢，Tommy，我10点出来，到时见
This is Jolene French, reporting from the African Children's Benefit Ball,
我是Jolene French，在非洲儿童义卖舞会为您报道
and I'm here with League President, Miss Hilly Holbrook.
我身边的是社团主席，Hily小姐
Thanks, Jolene. And I'm just so excited for the auction tonight, aren't you?
谢谢，Jolene，我很兴奋拍卖马上就要开始了，你呢？
I'm absolutely thrilled.
我兴奋极了
Thank you.
谢谢
Hi!
嗨！
Did you see what Miss Celia got on?
你看到Celia小姐的那身衣服了吗？
Lord, have mercy. Women better hold onto their husbands tonight.
主，仁慈啊，女人今晚最好把老公都抓牢了
Miss Leefolt been working on that dress for four weeks
Leefolt小姐这四个礼拜都在弄她那件衣服
and that's what she came up with?
结果就弄成那样？
- Here.
给
Kiss me.
吻我
Everybody enjoying the evening?
大家今晚都尽兴吗？
Let's give a nice round of applause for the help.
先向帮佣们献上我们的掌声！
For all the men and women who have helped make tonight possible.
向帮助过今晚义卖的男男女女
A cause I'm sure is dear to their hearts as well.
她们无疑都有颗善良的心
- Your cocktail. - Thank you.
-你的鸡尾酒 -谢谢
Honey, don't you think you've had enough to drink?
亲爱的，你不觉得今晚你喝得有点太多了吗？
I wish you'd try and eat something.
你最好吃点东西
I'm not having my stomach poke out.
我是不会让自己吐的
OK, OK, everybody, quiet down. I got the list of the winners!
好，大家，请安静，我要公布今晚的赢家了
OK.
好
The winner of the beautiful mink car coat is...
最美貂皮大衣的得主是...
...Charlotte Phelan!
- Congrats, Miss Phelan.
- 恭喜，Phelan小姐
Ladies, I hope your husbands take note of that.
小姐们，希望你们的老公都记下
Now it's time for the baked goods.
现在，该烘烤食物出场了
Ooh, yummy, yummy!
哦，好吃，好吃！
The highest bid in baked goods goes to
烘烤食物类最高拍价得主是
Minny Jackson's chocolate pie.
Minny Jackson的巧克力派
Congratulations...
恭喜...
...Hilly Holbrook!
...买主是Hilly Holbrook！
- Oh! Hilly. - That's funny.
-哦！Hilly -真有趣
I didn't bid on anything.
我什么都没拍
All right. And now it's time for Danica's strawberry jam.
好，接下来是Danica的草莓果酱
Shh!
嘘！
Congratulations, Hilly!
恭喜，Hily！
I didn't know you were a fan of Minny's pies.
我不知道你这么喜欢Minny的派
I've been wanting to talk to you all night.
今晚我一直想和你谈谈
Minny said why you won't be my friend.
Minny告诉我 你为什么不愿做我朋友了
It's 'cause you think me and Johnny went behind your back.
因为你认为当初我和Johnny背着你偷情
- Wait. I want to talk...
-等等，我想说...
Oh, no.
哦，不
I'm so sorry.
对不起
Come here, sweetheart.
过来，甜心
Let me bring you back to your table.
我带你回你的桌子去
- I'm really sorry. - it's all right. Don't worry about it.
-真是抱歉 -没关系，别放在心上
What are you trying to do to me? What are you and that nigra up to?
你想对我干什么？你和那黑鬼在捣什么鬼？
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不明白你的意思
You liar! Who did you tell?
你撒谎！你都告诉谁了？
Hilly, I got pregnant after you and Johnny broke up!
Hily，在你和Johnny分手后我才怀孕的！
- Oh, shit! - Shut up, Mother!
-哦，我去！ -闭嘴，妈妈！
Johnny never cheated on you.
Johnny从没背着你搞外遇
At least not with me.
至少不是和我
Oh, Johnny would never cheat on me.
哦，Johnny绝不会背着我搞外遇的
I'm so sorry! I thought you'd be tickled you won that pie!
抱歉！我以为赢下那个派你会很高兴，！
You tell that nigra, if she tells anybody, I will make her suffer!
你告诉那黑奴，她要敢告诉其他人，我就让她生不如死
Hey, that is enough.
嘿，够了
Celia.
Hey, baby, what's the matter?
嗨，宝贝，怎么了？
Oh!
哦！
Oh, shit. What a mess. Napkins.
哦，我去，一团糟，拿餐巾纸来
Why don't we get back to the auction?
为什么我们不回到拍卖上来？
- Next up, Debby's peppermint bark. - Celia!
-下一个是Debby的薄荷脆皮
It goes great with hot cocoa.
和热可可是绝配
Oh, just come on home with us tonight, Mother.
哦，今晚和我们一起回家吧，妈妈
No, thanks. I've got a pie to eat.
不用，谢谢，我还要吃派呢
You throw that pie away right now.
你马上把那派给扔了
I spent good money on this pie.
这派我可花了大价才买下的
I won it just for you.
特意为你买的
You signed me up?
你冒名替我？
I may have trouble remembering my own name, or what country I live in,
我也许会记不清自己的名字，生活在哪个国家
but there are two things I can't seem to forget:
但有两件事我记得很清楚
that my own daughter threw me into a nursing home,
就是我的亲生女儿送我进养老院
and that she ate Minny's shit.
还有她吃了Minny的便便
Good night.
晚安
- Hey, how about a nightcap? - Let's go.
-嗨，睡前再来一杯？ -走吧
I'm not right for this kind of life, Minny
我不适合这样的生活，Minny
I don't need a dining room table for 12 people.
我不需要一张能坐下12人的餐桌
I couldn't get two people over here if I begged.
即便我乞讨也拉不来两个人
I can't do this to Johnny anymore.
我再也不能这样对Johnny了
That's why I've gotta go back to Sugar Ditch.
所以我打算搬回Sugar Ditch
You can't move back to Sugar Ditch.
你不能搬回Sugar Ditch
Lord.
主啊
I reckon it's time you knew.
是时候让你知道了
Sit down.
坐下
So Miss Hilly thought you knew about the terrible awful.
所以Hily小姐以为你知道这件可怕的事
That you was making fun of her.
以为你在取乐她
It's my fault she pounced on you.
她这样对你是我的错
If you leave Mr. Johnny...
如果你离开Johnny先生
...then Miss Hilly done won the whole ball game.
...那么这次舞会Hily就真赢了
Then she done beaten me...
然后她也赢了我...
...and she done beat you.
...她赢了你
Thank you for telling me that.
谢谢你告诉我这些
Lord, look at all these pages. 266.
天，看这书厚的，266页
Mm-mm!
嗯！
So we just send it off? Just wait and see?
接下来我们把它寄出去？就等着瞧了？
Hope Miss Stein gonna publish it?
等Stein小姐出版它？
Well, I have one more story to type before I put it in the mail,
在放进信箱前我还有一个故事要写
but other than that, we're done.
除此之外，我们都完事了
Which one you got left?
还有哪个故事要写？
Uh, mine.
我的
I need to talk to you about Constantine.
我要和你谈谈Constantine
Oh, Eugenia, that was so long ago.
哦，Eugenia，那是多久之前的事了
What happened?
发生了什么？
Oh.
哦
What happened?
发生了什么？
She didn't give me a choice.
她让我别无选择
The Daughters of America had just appointed me state regent.
Daughters of America刚任命我为state regent
Grace Higginbotham, our esteemed president, came all the way down
备受尊敬的主席Grace Higginbotham为了颁奖典礼
from Washington, D.C., to our house for the ceremony.
一路从华盛顿赶来
- That's just beautiful. Look at that.
真是漂亮，快瞧瞧
She'd gotten so old and slow, Skeeter.
她又老又笨拙，Skeeter
Yes, ma'am.
是的，女人
It's such an honor that you came all this way.
真是荣幸，您大老远跑来
That's all right.
好了
- Hello, Miss Charlotte.
你好，Charlotte小姐
We were expecting you next week.
还以为你下礼拜才到
I decided to come early and surprise Mama.
我决定早点过来给妈妈个惊喜
- Oh.
哦
I'm entertaining.
我在宴请呢
Why don't you go around back. Wait in the kitchen.
你先绕路到后面厨房等着
Go on now.
快走
I am sorry.
抱歉
- Rachel, what are you doing?
-Rachel，你这是干什么？
I'm just doing as I was told, Miss Charlotte.
我不是在照你的吩咐做吗，Charlotte小姐
Going to the kitchen.
去厨房
But I'm going to see my mama first.
但我要先见妈妈
- Hello, Mama.
-你好，妈妈
Go on to the kitchen, baby. I'll be there directly.
去厨房，宝贝，我马上就来
You may put up with this kind of nonsense, but I do not.
这荒唐事是可忍，孰不可忍也
Get out of this house, Rachel.
滚出这房子，Rachel
You heard her. Go on, girl.
你听到她说的了，快走吧，女孩
Miss Charlotte, let me take her to the kitchen. Come on, baby. Let's go.
Charlotte小姐，让我带她到厨房，来，宝贝，我们走
Charlotte.
Both of you.
你们俩
Leave. Now.
都走，现在
Come on, Mama.
走，妈妈
Come on now.
走吧
Constantine didn't do anything wrong.
Constantine并没做错
And you love Rachel. I know you do.
而你爱Rachel，我知道的
She was our president. What was I supposed to do?
她可是我们主席，我能怎么办？
She did you the biggest favor of your life. She taught me everything.
她帮了你人生一个大忙，她教我长大成人
Well, you idolized her too much. You always have.
你太崇拜她了，你总是这样
I needed someone to look up to.
我总要崇拜某人的
Well, I...
这个，我...
I went to her house the next day, but she had already gone.
第二天我就上她家，但她已经走了
How could you not tell me all this?
你怎能瞒着我这事？
Because I didn't want to upset you during your final exams.
那时你就要期末考了 我不想打扰你
I knew you'd blame me, and it wasn't my fault!
我知道你会怪我，但不是我的错！
I have to go find her. She needs me.
我要去找她，她需要我
- Eugenia. - What?
-Eugenia -什么？
We sent your brother up to Chicago to bring Constantine home.
我们让你哥哥去芝加哥接Constantine回家
When he got there...
当他到达时...
...she had died.
...她已经去世了
You broke her heart.
你伤透了她的心
I'm...I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
对不起，对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起
They printed a few thousand copies
他们印制了几千本
with the worst advance Miss Stein had ever seen.
Stein小姐没见过比这更糟的发行预售
Baby, what you doing with Alicia book? You can't read.
宝贝，你拿着Alicia的书干什么？你又不识字
They sent Miss Skeeter $600. She broke that money up and gave it to each of us.
他们寄给Skeeter小姐600美元，她把钱平分给大家
Divided 13 ways, that came to about $46 each.
13份，每份有46美元
Y'all finish your homework.
你们赶紧做作业
Aibileen. Aibileen!
We just got this from Miss Skeeter. Look at it.
我刚收到Skeeter小姐的信，看看
Look at it.
快看看
Look at it!
看看！
- Minny, we're rich!
Minny，我们发财了！
"She fired me for using her inside toilet.
“她解雇了我，因为我使用了她的厕所
Put me out in a storm and told me never to come back. But I did come back.
她把我赶进暴风雨里，叫我永远不要回去，但我回去了
I came back with a pie I had baked to say I'm sorry.
我回去了，拿着我满怀歉意的派
I watched her eat..."
我看着她吃...”
Well, it's a wonderful book, Hilly
真是本不错的书，Hily
Filled with gripping testimonials from Mississippi's housekeepers.
全是密西西比女主妇们的故事
OK, Mama. I need to run.
好，妈妈，我要挂了
Well. You should read the book, Hilly. it's quite scandalous.
你真该看看这书，Hily，全是丑闻
Sounds like... Jackson, if you ask me.
好像就...发生在Jackson，你问我的话
Quite scandalous.
大丑闻啊
What book?
什么书？
What's it called again?
书名叫什么
The Help. H-E-L-P.
相助
There it is.
看那
You told me to write something good.
你叫我写出一些好的
- Something I believed in. - It's not what I believe in.
-写下我所坚信的 -我可不信那一套
That joke you pulled with Hilly with the toilets, that's funny.
你和Hily开的那个马桶玩笑，那个有趣
Why would you do this to us?
你为什么这样对我们？
I don't even know why you care.
我都不明白你为什么关心
- What? - Things are fine around here.
-什么？ -这里一切本来都挺好
Why go stir up trouble?
你为什么要去搅合？
Trouble's already here, Stuart.
这里本来就不太平，Stuart
I had to tell you this. You needed to know.
我必须告诉你，你应该知道
Goddamn right I needed to know. You should have told me this from the start.
该死的太对了，你一开始就该告诉我
You're a selfish woman, Skeeter.
你是个自私的女人，Skeeter
Stuart.
I think you're better off being alone.
我想你还是单身一人吧
Did you get to that part yet that I was telling you about?
你看到我说的那一节了吗？
Don't read ahead, whatever you do.
别继续往下看了
"What you done put up in this?"
“你在里面放了什么”
"She Said, 'My Shit."'
“她说‘我的屎’”
What's the matter, Hilly?
怎么了，Hily？
- Get off of me! Get off! - Ouch! Stop hitting me!
-别碰我！别碰！ -哦！别打我了！
I heard that Betty character might be Mary Elizabeth.
我听说书中的Betty就是Mary Elizabeth
It's not Jackson.
这事不发生在这
And that book is garbage. I bet the whole thing is made up by some nigra.
那书就是垃圾，我敢说整本书就是某个黑鬼虚构出来的
And Jolene, didn't your mama
Jolene，你妈妈在她遗嘱里
leave Cora to you in her will?
不是把Cora留给了你吗？
Yes, but that's not odd, is it? Happens all the time, right?
是，但不奇怪啊，这事哪都有，对吧？
The book is not about Jackson.
这书不关Jackson的事
What the hell?
什么？
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
- I've contacted my lawyer.
我已经联系律师了
Hibbie Goodman? He's the best libel attorney in the state.
Hibbie Goodman，他可是本州最棒的诽谤罪律师
Oh, Missy, you're going to jail.
哦，小姐，你就等着坐牢吧
You can't prove anything.
你证明不了什么
Oh, I 100 percent know you wrote it. Nobody else in town is as tacky as you.
我百分之百确定就是你写的，镇里没人像你这么没教养
You don't know anything, Hilly
你什么都不知道，Hily
- Oh, I don't, do I?
哦，我不知道？
You tell Aibileen the next time she wants to write
你告诉Aibileen下一次她想写
about my dear friend Elizabeth...
关于我好友Elizabeth...
Uh-huh.Remember her? Had you in her wedding.
还记得她吧，你参加过她婚礼
Let's just say Aibileen ought to have been a little bit smarter
Aibileen本该更聪明些
before putting in about that L-shaped scratch
她不该在可怜的Elizabeth餐桌上
in poor Elizabeth's dining table.
刻下那个L
And that nigger Minny, do I have plans for her.
至于那个黑鬼Minny，她给我等着瞧
- Careful, Hilly. That's chapter 12.
说话注意，Hily，看看第12章
Don't give yourself away now.
可别把自己给暴露了
That was not me!
那不是我！
I've come to tell your mother what a hippie you've become.
我就是来告诉你妈妈你是怎样一个嬉皮士
She's going to be disgusted by you.
她一定会被你恶心透的
Why, Hilly. Is everything OK, you two?
为什么，Hily，一切都好吗，你俩？
Oh, Mrs. Phelan.
哦，Phelan夫人
Hilly, you're a sweaty mess. Are you ill?
Hily，你怎么汗淋淋的，生病了吗？
No, ma'am.
没有，夫人
Darling, oh, no husband wants to come home and see that.
亲爱的，没有哪个丈夫回家愿看到老婆这个样子
Oh.
哦
I didn't have time to get fixed up.
我还没时间化妆
You know, Hilly, if I didn't know any better,
你看，Hily，我本该提醒你的
I'd say you've been eating too much pie.
你不该吃那么多派
Mrs. Phelan, I came here...
Phelan夫人，我到这...
In fact, I'm sure of it.
事实上，我一清二楚
Now you get your raggedy ass off my porch.
现在把你的烂屁股挪出我的走廊
Go on.
消失
Get off my property. Now!
滚出我的房子，立刻！
Before we all get one of those disgusting things on our lips!
趁我们还没被你嘴巴上那恶心东西感染!
Eugenia. Take me inside, please.
Eugenia，扶我进去
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
Skeeter, do you have plans tomorrow?
Skeeter，明天你有事吗？
- No, ma'am. - Good.
-没有，夫人 -很好
Because we are going shopping.
因为我们要去血拼一番
No single daughter of mine is going to New York City
我的单身女儿代表着伟大的密西西比
representing the great state of Mississippi
没有一个像样的衣橱
without a proper cosmopolitan wardrobe.
怎能去闯纽约呢
How do you know about New York?
你怎么知道纽约的事？
Oh, well, Miss Stein called last night.
哦，Stein小姐昨晚打来电话
Courage sometimes skips a generation.
勇气这天赋看来是隔代传了
Thank you for bringing it back to our family.
谢谢你把勇气重新带回家里
I can't leave you like this.
你这个样子我不能离开
Eugenia, I have made a decision.
Eugenia，我做了个决定
My health's been on the uptick these last few weeks,
最近几周我的身体有所好转
and I know the doctor says it's some kind of last strength nonsense,
我知道这就是医生所说的回光返照
but I have decided not to die.
但我没打算去死
Oh, Mama.
哦，妈妈
It's too late. I tried calling Fanny Mae's
太迟了，我打电话给Fanny Mae
to make all your hair appointments for the next 20 years,
为你预约接下来二十年的美发服务
- but they wouldn't allow it.
但他们说不行
I have never been more proud of you.
我从未如此为你感到自豪
Thank you.
谢谢
Mama.
妈妈
Need some help with those?
需要帮忙吗？
Minny.
- Miss Celia! - Minny, hey, stop! Minny!
-Celia小姐 -Minny，嗨，站住！Minny
- Miss Celia! - Minny!
-Celia小姐！ -Minny！
- Stay back! - I'm not here to hurt you! Girl...
-别过来！ -我不会伤害你的！
You gonna put the stick down?
能把棒子放下吗？
Listen, Celia finally told me about the babies.
听我说，Celia终于把孩子的事告诉我了
All of them.
所有的
But I also know, the minute you started working here,
我也知道，打从你在这工作开始
she started getting better.
她一天比一天好
So, you saved her life.
你拯救了她
You knew I was here the whole time?
你一直都知道我在这？
Fried chicken and okra on the first night?
第一晚的炸鸡腿和秋葵荚？
Y'all could have at least put some cornpone on the table.
你们至少放点玉米饼在桌上
No.
不行
I couldn't let you eat no more cornpone, Mr. Johnny.
我可不能让你再吃玉米饼了，Johnny先生
Thanks to you, now I've had to let out every pair of pants I own.
多亏了你，现在我的裤子都得改大一圈
You just leave that.
那个给我
Here you go.
给
Let's head on up the house.
一起回房子去吧
What's this?
这都是什么？
I cooked it all by myself.
全都是我自己做的
Yes, she did. She was up all night.
是的，她忙活了一晚上
I wanted to do something special.
我想做点特别的东西
I wanted to say thank you.
我要谢谢你
So...
那...
...I ain't losing my job?
...我不会失业吧？
No, you got a job here for the rest of your life.
这辈子在这都有你的工作
If you want it.
只要你愿意
That's a mile-high meringue, Miss Celia.
看来我有得做了，Celia小姐
- Please. - Thank you
-请 -谢谢.
You remember to check the thighs?
鸡大腿检查过吧？
- Mm-hm. Cooked clean through. - Ain't pink in the middle?
-嗯，烧透了 -里面不是红色吧
Uh-uh. Just the way you taught me.
就照你教我做的
Looky here.
来点这个
That table of food gave Minny the strength she needed.
这一桌的食物给了Minny勇气
She took her babies out from under Leroy and never went back.
她带着孩子彻底离开了Leroy
What are all these cars doing out here? Are we late?
怎么这么多车？我们迟了吗？
No, we ain't late.
没有，我们没迟
Why ain't you singing?
你怎么不哼两句？
We got to worry about getting in there and getting our seats.
我担心进去后还找得到座么？
Come on now, we late!
快，我们迟了！
- Who we clapping for? - Honey, we clapping for you!
-我们在为谁鼓掌？ -亲爱的，为你！
Come on down, Sister Clark!
快上来，Clark教友！
Come on.
快
来
All right, all right.
好了，好了
Now, uh... this is an important time in our community.
此时...是我们社区的重要一刻
And we have to thank you for what you have done.
我们感谢你的所作所为
Now...
现在...
We know you couldn't put your name in here,
我们知道你不能在书上署名
so we all signed our own.
所以我们签上了自己的
Thank you.
谢谢
Come on, now. Come on.
收下吧，快，收下
Churches over two counties signed our books. All for you and me.
两个县的教友在书上签了名，为了你和我
It's beautiful.
真美
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I got a job offer from Harper and Row in New York.
我得到了纽约Harper and Row的工作
Congratulations!
恭喜！
- I'm not taking it. - What you mean you're not taking it?
-我没有接受 -什么叫你没有接受？
I can't just leave you two here
我不能就这样扔下你俩
when things are getting bad from the mess that I created.
在事情由于我的书开始变糟之际
No. If bad things happen, ain't nothing you can do about it.
不用，如果坏事要发生，你也无能为力
And now it's for a reason we can be proud of.
现在总算有件值得骄傲的事了
I don't mean to rub salt in your wound,
我不是要在你伤口上撒盐
but you ain't got a good life here in Jackson.
但在Jackson这里你的生活真不怎样
Plus, your mama's getting better.
况且，你妈妈身体也见好转
You ain't got nothing left here but enemies in the Junior League.
在这里除了社团里的敌人 你什么都没有了
You done burned every bridge there is.
桥牌聚会被你彻底毁了
And you ain't never gonna get another man in this town.
而且在镇里你也找不到任何男人
- Everybody know that.
这个大家都知道
So don't walk your white butt to New York, run it!
所以还不快去纽约，赶紧滴！
Looky here, Miss Skeeter. I'm gonna take care of Aibileen.
看，Skeeter小姐，我会照顾Aibileen
And she's gonna take care of me.
她也会照顾我
Go find your life, Miss Skeeter.
去闯你自己的人生吧，Skeeter小姐
Aibileen, can you come in here, please?
Aibileen，你过来下，好吗？
Good morning.
早上好
Aibileen, the silver I lent Elizabeth last week.
Aibileen，我上礼拜借给Elizabeth的银器
It not polished good?
擦的不够亮吗？
Humidity been fighting me on polishing day.
那天湿气很大 很不好擦
When you returned it, three pieces were missing from the felt wrapper.
你还回来的时候少了三件
- A fork and two spoons.
一把叉子和两个汤匙
Let me... Let me go check in the kitchen. Maybe I left some behind.
我...再去厨房找找，也许落在什么地方了
You know as well as I do that silver's not in the kitchen.
你我心里都明白银器不在厨房
You check in Mae Mobley's bed?
Mae Mobley的床上你看过没？
Since the Lil Man was born, she been putting things...
自从Lil Man出生，她一直把东西...
Do you hear her, Elizabeth?
你听到没，Elizabeth?
She's trying to blame it on a toddler.
她想把责任推给小孩子
I ain't got no silver.
我什么银器都没拿
She says she doesn't have them.
她说她没拿
Then it behooves me to inform you that you are fired, Aibileen.
那我不得不通知你 你被解雇了，Aibileen
And I'll be calling the police.
然后我会报警
Aibee, my throat hurts.
Aibee，我的嗓子疼
I'll go get some syrup, Miss Leefolt.
我去拿些糖浆，Leefolt小姐
Elizabeth can take care of her own children.
Elizabeth自会照顾她的孩子
- I'll go get the cough syrup. - Come here, Lil Man.
-我去拿咳嗽糖浆 -来，Lil Man
I'm OK.
我能行
I didn't steal no silver.
我什么银器也没偷
Maybe I can't send you to jail for what you wrote,
也许我不能因为你写的东西送你进监狱
but I can send you for being a thief.
但你做贼的话 我就能
I know something about you. Don't you forget that.
我知道你的事，你别忘了
From what Yule Mae says, there's a lot of time to write letters in jail.
从Yule Mae那我知道监狱里有不少时间来写信
Plenty of time to write the truth about you. And the paper is free.
足够多的时间写下你那些事，纸还是免费的
- Nobody will believe what you wrote! - I don't know!
-没人会相信你写的东西 -我不知道
I been told I'm a pretty good writer. Already sold a lot of books.
大家都说我是个好作者，书已经卖了很多
Call the police, Elizabeth.
去报警，Elizabeth
All you do is scare and lie to try to get what you want.
为了得到你想要的 你只会威胁和撒谎
Aibileen, stop!
Aibileen，停！
You a godless woman.
你个目无上帝的女人
Ain't you tired, Miss Hilly?
你不累吗，Hily小姐？
Ain't you tired?
不累吗？
Aibileen, you have to go now.
Aibileen，你得走了
Don't go, Aibee.
别走，Aibee
Baby, you need to get back to bed.
宝贝，你快回床上去
- Please don't leave. -I gots to, baby. I am so sorry.
-请不要走 -我必须走，宝贝，抱歉
Are you going to take care of another little girl?
你是要去照顾其他女孩子吗？
No, that's not the reason.
不，不是因为那个
I don't want to leave you, but it's time for me to retire.
我不想离开你，但我该退休了
- You're my last little girl. - No!
-你是我最后一个女孩 -不要
Baby. Baby.
宝贝
I need you to remember everything I told you, OK?
我要你记住我跟你说过的话，好吗？
- OK. - You remember what I told you?
-好 -你还记得我跟你说的吗？
You is kind. You is smart.
你很善良，你很聪明
You is important.
你很重要
That's right, Baby Girl.
对，宝贝
Don't go, Aibee.
别走，Aibee
I gots to, baby.
我得走了，宝贝
You give my sweet girl a chance.
你记得给我的女孩一个机会
Mae Mobley was my last baby.
Mae Mobley是我照顾的最后一个孩子
In just ten minutes, the only life l knew was done.
不到十分钟里，我以前熟知的生活彻底远去
Aibee!
God says we need to love our enemies.
上帝说我们要爱我们的敌人
No!
不！
It hard to do.
这很难做到
But it can start by telling the truth.
但可以从说真话做起
No one had ever asked me what it felt like to be me.
没人问过我做我自己是什么感觉
Once I told the truth about that...
要我来说的话...
...I felt free.
...我感觉自由
And I got to thinking about all the people l know.
我开始考虑认识的每个人
And the things I seen and done.
我所见过经历过的
My boy, Treelore, always said we going to have a writer in the family one day.
我的孩子 Treelore总说 我们家迟早要出个作家
I guess it's gonna be me.
我想那人是我